Ladies and gentlemen, debut
Ladies and gentlemen, débutage
The second stage of Sy opponents
The second stage of Sy opponents
Please lead the Dr sprawl
Please lead the Dr sprawl
yes
ええ
Is there abalone in it at night?
晚上裡面有鮑魚嗎?
No! What a pity!
沒有啊!可惜!
Very important!
很重要!
we got your opening
我們把你的開場講出來了
Welcome to this
歡迎各位參加這次的
Knowledge Banquet of the Month
這個月的知識獎宴
me a few months ago
我前幾個月
After taking over the post of maternity home
接了婦院者的職務之後
one more job
多了一份工作
is to host the Knowledge Awards Banquet
就是主持知識獎宴
it's good
這是很好
happy work
愉快的工作
Because I learn a lot every time
因為每次都學到很多
indeed a prize
確實是獎宴
I believe this time is no exception
我相信這次也不例外
this time our
這次我們的
The main prize is Chen Zhiyi
主獎人是陳志義
Dr. Chen Zhiyi
博士陳志義
He is a cell of the Chinese Academy
他是中文院的細胞
individual organisms
於個體生物
researcher at the Institute of
學研究所的研究員
is in
是在
Culture University's Department of Oceanography Biology Group
文化大學的海洋學系生物組
get a bachelor's degree
拿到學士學位
later in Taiwan
之後在台灣
The joy of National Taiwan University
台灣大學的愉悅
Institute of Science for a Master's Degree
科學研究所得到碩士學位
Then at National Taiwan University
然後在台大學
graduate School
研究所
It is a unit in the School of Life Sciences
是生命科學院裡面的一個單位
get a doctorate
拿到博士學位
Then he went to a very famous research institute in the UK
之後他到英國一個非常有名的研究所
Call the Sanger Institute
叫Sanger Institute
Sanger won the Nobel Prize
Sanger是拿到諾貝爾獎的
for DNA sequencing
為了DNA的定序
the researcher who won the nobel prize
得到諾貝爾獎的那個研究員
the scholar
是那個學者
He is his Institute
他是他的Institute
And in 2003 to the Institute of Zoology of Central Plains Institute
和2003年到中原院的動物研究所
This institute is now
這個研究所現在就是
Cell Individual Biology Institute
細胞的個體生物研究所
Working at Linhai Research Station
在臨海研究站任職
Now a researcher at that institute
現在是那個研究所的研究員
Dr Chen has studied marine life for many years
陳博士多年來研究海洋生物的
Antibacterial ecology
抗菌生態
that's his topic today
就是他今天的主題
Fluorescence
同時他對螢光
admiring the earth
觀賞於有大地
do research and development work
做研發的工作
I don't know if today will be better than these few
不知道今天會不會比這幾個
That's a very sad hope
那是非常委屈的希望
Maybe
也許
In the future, you can also get from him
以後各位也可以從他那邊
Learn more about this very wronged one
多了解一下這個非常委屈的一個
the result of his research and development
他的研發的成果
then he
然後他
Dr. Chen
陳博士
won many awards
拿到多項的獎項
include
包括
Academician Yang Jiangfa
楊江發院士
Outstanding Young Scholar Award in Agricultural Sciences
傑出農業科學年輕學者獎
in the National Innovation Awards
在國家新創獎
he also used to be
他也曾經當過
Director of Taiwan Society of Marine Biotechnology
台灣海洋生物技術學會的理事
OK, then we give warm applause
好 那我們就熱烈的掌聲
welcome thank you dr chen
歡迎謝謝陳博士
Thank you Vice President for your report
謝謝副院長的報告
Today is
今天是
The first knowledge missing in the end of the year
不完年第一個知識想念的
first knowledge miss
第一個知識想念
I'm here to say goodbye to everyone
我現在這邊跟大家拜個晚年
Hope you all have a happy new year and all the best
希望大家能夠在幾年新年快樂萬事如意
Thank you all very much for coming here tonight to listen to knowledge miss
那也非常感謝大家能夠在今天晚上來這邊聆聽知識想念
There is what I talked about eating fish today but not
有我所主講的今天吃魚而沒
Antimicrobial status of fish could be cancer-fighting
魚類的抗菌態將可能是抗癌
or antimicrobial psychotropic drugs
或是抗菌的心態藥物
then i will be silent
那我就沉寂了
I am from Jiao Township, Yilan County
我是來自於宜蘭縣交鄉
We have a forest sea research station over there
我們那邊有一個林海研究站
Generally, you may be unfamiliar with the Linhai Research Station
一般大家可能對林海研究站比較陌生
But wait a minute we have a few eras
不過等一下我們有幾張時代
Let me introduce you to the Linhai Research Station
跟大家介紹一下林海研究站
then i just
那我剛
I was just outside and the deputy dean asked everyone a question
我剛在外面副院長問問大家一個問題
Tell me, have you eaten any fish tonight?
說大家今天晚上有沒有吃魚
that's okay
那沒有關係
I asked everyone if you have eaten fish like this today
我問大家今天有沒有吃過魚這樣子
I think Yilan County is becoming more and more important
我想宜蘭縣還是越來越非常重要的一個
a source of food
一個食物的來源
Especially now that everyone pays attention to health preservation
尤其在現在大家講求養生
And recently there is love flu
還有最近還有情流感
killed a bunch of geese
殺了一堆鵝
killed a bunch of chickens
殺了一堆雞
pressure age
壓年紀跟
I can't tell the difference between the ear and the ear
壓分耳都殺雜分不清
Then the best way is to eat fish
然後最好的方式就是吃魚
So the topic I'm talking about today
所以我今天講的這個主題
I hope everyone will go back in the future
希望大家將來回去以後
can eat more fish
能夠多吃一點魚
Then help our water mountain farming industry in Taiwan
然後幫助我們台灣的水山養殖業
can develop with us
能夠跟我們發展
Then we can produce more relevant research output in our marine biotechnology
然後在我們海洋生物科技裡面能夠更有相關的研究產出
To take care of everyone's fasting on the food measurement
來照顧大家在量食上面的一個空腹
Alright, so today we are going to talk about what is called the anti-ying platform
好啦,所以我們今天要先講什麼叫做抗營台
That is, the anti-ying platform is a very interesting thing
就是抗營台是一個很有趣的東西
Let me tell you first, ask if you eat fish
我先跟大家講,問問大家有沒有吃魚
I think everyone must have seen these kinds of fish in the vegetable market
我想大家上菜市場一定都有看過這幾種魚
Except for this fish, everyone may be unfamiliar
除了這一隻魚,大家可能比較陌生以外
Everyone must have seen grouper
大家一定會有看過石斑魚
Yes, everyone has seen black abalone, right?
有,那大家也有看過烏鮑魚嘛對不對
when i went to the market
我從上菜市場的時候
My mother buys black abalone or buys these fish
我老媽買烏鮑魚或是買這些魚
he must tell me
他一定跟我講
That salmon wheel, that wheel isn't good
那把鮭魚輪輪,那輪輪不堂貝
right, is that so
對不對,是這樣嘛
So put the salmon wheel in the case of the wheel
所以把鮭魚輪輪輪的情況之下
Why is this fish sick?
就是這隻魚幹嘛生病了
may have been ill before his death
可能在他死亡之前可能有生病
The sickness is in the aquatic oxygen body
生的病在水產氧體裡面
Fish diseases are somewhat similar to human diseases
魚病就有一點類似人的疾病
Then this black abalone and this fish like flounder
那這個烏鮑魚還有這個是類似比目魚的魚
I'm going to report to you now
我現在要跟大家報告一下
Because I first write the names of these anti-Philippine sellers here
因為我先把這幾個抗菲律賣的名字寫在這邊
because everyone can know
是因為讓大家能夠知道
Let's wait and we'll introduce these protagonists to you
我們等一下我們會跟大家介紹這幾個主角
We translate it into EBCD
我們把它翻譯成EBCD
Because its English name is EBCD1
因為它的英文名字叫EBCD1
Its content is to hope that everyone can see the anti-Philippine sales
它的內容就是希望大家看到抗菲律賣
know that it will give B to E in the future
就知道它將來會把B給E之處
So I translated it into this Chinese
所以我把它翻成這個中文
on top of the turtle fish
在烏龜魚上面
This is our common Niroka turtle fish
這個是我們常見的尼羅卡的烏龜魚
that turtle fish
那個烏龜魚
It's Moshan Piccolo Turtle Fish
就是摸山比克烏龜魚
They all have different anti-Philippines
它們身上都有不同的抗菲律賣
name sold against philippines
抗菲律賣的名字
will have different names for different fish species
會因為不同的魚種而有不同的名字
But because of its structure in different fish
但是因為它的結構在不同魚身上
is also different
也是不一樣的
Each anti-philippine is sold on a variety of different fish
每一個抗菲律賣在各種不同的魚身上
it will have different functions
它會有不同的功能
I'll report back to you later
等一下我會再跟大家報告一下
Now let me tell you an interesting story
那現在來跟大家講一個有趣的故事
Why do we have to tell the story of Shui Shanyang
為什麼我們要講到水山洋的故事
I ran away to make a cup of wine.
把酒杯都跑去泡杯了
I'm going to report to you now
現在要跟大家報告
Nashuishanyang is the farming industry of grouper
那水山洋就是石斑魚的養殖產業
Taiwan's aquaculture aquaculture is very meticulous
台灣水養殖水養殖繁工非常的細緻
you may not know
大家可能有所不知
Usually we may take the car to the maintenance shop
通常我們可能把車子開到保養廠
A master can do a lot
一個師傅就可以修了很多的
Let's say we go to the Ford service shop
譬如說我們到福特保養廠
This master who may receive you
可能接待你的這個師傅
The whole car can be refueled and maintained
可以把整台車子加加油要保養一下
But not in the year of the aquaculture industry
但是在水養殖產業年不是這樣子
each different region
每一個不同的地區
every different period
每一個不同的時期
it will have different breeders
它會有不同的養殖戶
Or breeding professionals to do farming work
或養殖專業人員去做養殖的工作
In this picture, let me tell you
在這張圖我跟大家講一下
This is a grouper breeding process
這是一個石斑魚的養殖過程
grouper it has what is called inch seconds
石斑魚它有所謂的寸秒
Of course at different times
當然在不同的時期
For example, this time only the time to eat mosquitoes
譬如說這次只有吃蚊蟲的時期
Or the time to eat bee-snapped shrimp
或是吃蜂蜒蝦的時期
in different periods
在不同的時期裡面
They all have different bacterial infections
它們都會有不同的細菌感染
or viral infection
或是病毒感染
For example, the grouper mainly has many
譬如說石斑魚它最主要有很多的
neurochemotherapy virus
神經化療室病毒
or have many bacterial infections
或是有很多細菌感染
e.g. fungal infection
譬如說胡菌感染
or so-called intense infection
或是所謂的烈濃感染
or other infections such as pointworm
或是其他的譬如說百點蟲的感染
The lethality of these infections
那這些感染的致死力
In fact, some have reached the so-called 100% fatality rate
其實有些達到所謂的100%的致死率
Wait a minute and I will report a Hu Jun to everyone
等一下我會跟大家報告一個胡俊
A Hu Jun made in our laboratory
我們實驗室做的一種胡俊
This Hu Jun is my last from college
這胡俊是我從持續大學
Obtained by Mr. Chen Junyao's laboratory
陳俊堯老師實驗室得到的
This Hu Jun is very interesting
這胡俊很有趣
You may not believe that we are sick
大家可能不相信我們生病了
we are sick
我們人生病了
live in hospital
住到醫院
The hospital may also give you first aid and antibiotic treatment
醫院可能還會幫你做急救做抗生素的治療
come soon
快的話到
I'll talk about the proxy certificate later
到等一下我會講的代學證
or acute
或是急性的
Acute pharmacology certificate
急性代學證
Maybe in about a week, people's lives will be goodbye
可能大概一個禮拜人的生命就會再見
But do you believe it?
但是你們相信嗎?
From our discovery of infection
從我們發現感染
People who may have raised fish before could not understand
之前可能養魚的人都搞不清楚
how did this fish die
這個魚到底是怎麼死的
But he found that within 24 hours the fish in the whole area
但他發現24小時內整區的魚
all will die for you
全部都會死給你看
Then die and show you later
然後死給你看以後
you may see
大家可能就會看到
some fish just cuddle fish
有些魚就是把魚摟摟
ok
好啦
we'll talk next
我們接下來講
When I went to Linghai Research Station
在我去靈海研究站的時候
When I first went to Linghai Research Station
我剛開始去靈海研究站的時候
There is an interesting story that
有一個有趣的故事就是
We hope that at Linghai Research Station
我們希望在靈海研究站
Some are the same as Taiwan carry
有一些跟台灣隨身一樣
A job that can assist Taiwan's water mountain farming industry
能夠協助台灣水山養殖產業的一個工作
Because everyone eats fish like everyone sees
因為大家吃魚就像大家看到了
have many emotions
有很多情有感
that duck or goose will die
那個鴨子或是鵝會死亡一樣
no robin dies
沒有鴝會死亡
so at that time
所以在那時候呢
Director Guo Qingyin will tell me one thing
我們郭慶銀主任就交代我一件事
what he wishes to be able to do
他希望能夠做什麼
make an early morning thing
做一個早日的東西
Able to assist Taiwan's water mountain farming industry
能夠協助台灣的水山養殖產業
The problem of allowing illness
允病的問題
Then I wanted to say
後來那時候就想說
how do i solve it
我是要怎麼來解決
What kinds of infections?
這幾種問題的感染呢
virus infection at that time
那時候病毒感染
In my press release called The Laboratory of Inorganic Therapy
在我的資訊稿叫做無機療療的實驗室
have done well
已經做得很好的
i think i do virus infection maybe
我想我做病毒感染可能
So I think
所以我覺得
Bacterial infection may be a very interesting thing
細菌感染或許是一個很有趣的東西
Because bacteria can kill invisible
因為細菌能夠殺人於無形
But it is possible to use a
但是能夠以一個
a tiny bacterium
很那麼小的一個細菌
it allows fish
它可以讓魚
or cause disease in living things
或是讓生物產生了疾病
That's a disease Hu Jun got
那這是胡俊所得到的一個疾病
It's a picture taken from the internet
是從網路上摘錄下來的一個圖片
in the grouper or stack
在石斑裡或是疊
or Elephant Gauge
或是大象規
You can see when Hu Jun is infected
你可以看到胡俊感染的時候
In case of swelling
有腫脹的情形
In fact, this is because when the later outbreak
其實這是因為後期爆發的時候
it inhales and reproduces in large numbers
它吸進會大量的繁殖
lots of splits
大量的分裂
Then such a sudden illness occurs in Su Ni
然後在宿泥裡面產生這樣一個急病
we help
我們幫人呢
in case of acute illness
於產生急病的時候
just to give medicine
就是要投藥
From the concept of farming
從養殖的概念
For example, I went to university from inside
譬如說我從裡面大學
The concept of farming in those days
那年代養殖的概念
In fact, we were raising grass shrimp at that time
其實那時候在養草蝦
or raise some fish
或是養一些魚類
you may not know
大家可能有所不知
in their farming industry
在他們養殖的產業
all in cash
都是現金交易的
at that time in university
那時候在裡面大學
Just go to the aquaculture area to implement
就是去水館養殖區實行
When I went there to see how people raise fish
去那邊看人家怎麼養魚的時候
I just discovered aquarium farming later
我才後來發現水館養殖
It's a very shallow industry
這是一個非常淺益的產業
but
但是呢
at that moment
在那個當下
What to do if the fish is sick
魚得病了怎麼辦
as I just reported to you
就像我剛剛跟大家報告的
one night
一個晚上
if all you raise
如果所有你養的
All 10,000 silky fish are fighting
一萬條烏骨魚全部邊斗
look
你看
Then you don't feel very
那你是不感覺到非常的
very frustrated
非常的沮喪
those fish
那這些魚
if not dying
如果還沒有要死
before you die
還沒有死之前
because what will do ? drug
因為會做什麼?下藥
What is drugging?
什麼叫下藥呢?
Just give some chemicals or antibiotics
就是會下一些化學藥劑或是抗生素
to treat these infections
來治療這些疾病感染
bacterial infection
細菌性的感染
Let me introduce to you first
我現在先跟大家介紹一下
aquaculture once upon a time
水產養殖從前
Chemical reagents commonly used in the past
從前時常用的化學試劑
For example, peacock eating worry
譬如說孔雀食慮
or antibiotics
或是抗生素
For example, this antibiotic
譬如說這個抗生素
N-O killing heart
N-O殺心
It is a medicine for animals
它是一種動物專用的藥物
These things will be mixed in the ingredients
這些東西它會混在食材裡面
forehead
頭額
Then you go to therapy for five days
然後你去治療五天
your fish will be fine
你的魚就可以好了
Why is it good? For example, peacock eats worry
為什麼可以好?譬如說孔雀食慮
Klebsiella spp
它可以對大腸感染的科雷波殺紋師菌
many different bacteria
很多不同的細菌
It has a bactericidal effect
它都有殺菌的效果
but
但是
everyone knows
大家也知道
these things will
這些東西會
coping with the food chain
應付在食物鏈上面
let everyone see
讓大家看到
horseshoe perch
馬菌尿鱸
Very shiny fish eaten into the stomach
很光亮的魚吃到肚子裡面
These things will also eat into your stomach
這些東西也會吃到你的肚子裡面去了
so
所以
So what's going on? Bacteria in the natural environment
所以會造成什麼?自然環境裡面的細菌
So-called drug resistance and limited drug production
所謂的藥物抗性跟藥物產有限
These two things deeply affect what we will talk about later
這兩種東西深深地影響到我們後面要講的東西
Why? Because bacteria it mutates
為什麼?因為細菌它會做突變
it will survive
它會為了生存
Just like us human beings also in order to survive
就像我們人也為了要生存
we will work very hard
我們會很努力的要去打拚
work hard
在工作上要打拚
Bacteria will also work very hard
細菌它也會很努力的去打拚
survive
生存下來
When a drug develops a resistance or drug miscarriage
當藥物產生了一個抗性或藥物產流
in this natural environment
在這個自然環境裡面的時候
we're in big trouble
我們就麻煩大了
Because of the relationship through the food chain
因為透過食物鏈的關係
will enter the human body
就會進到人體裡面
Let's talk about sex
我們現在來講性會
CGMP medicines
CGMP的藥品裡面
it has a product called mecon cream
它有一個叫做美康乳膏
Everyone probably used it
大家可能都會用過
In the medicine on the Department of Human Medicine
在人類醫學系上面的用藥裡面
You can see that it's all made of antibiotics.
你可以看到這裡面都是抗生素的組成
For example, Neumicin
譬如說Neumicin
this drug
這種藥物
You can see it's all clearly written
你可以看到它都寫得很清楚
now you go inside the pharmacy
在現在你們到藥房裡面
when buying any medicine
去買任何的藥物的時候
They will all be in the drug
它們都會在藥品的
on the trick table
那個迷技表上面
will be detailed in the form
表單裡面都會詳列
what are these drugs for
這些藥物是在幹嘛的
it will also tell you about its sex
它也會跟你講它的性
What are the indications
適應症是什麼
He will also adopt what is his potency
他也會領養他的效能是什麼
Do you think that these antibiotics are really magic medicines after seeing these effects?
大家看到這些效能有沒有覺得這些抗生素真的是神藥
So when I was a kid I thought antibiotics were really the magic drug
所以我在我小時候我覺得抗生素真的是神藥
Because it can treat many diseases
因為它可以治療好多好多的疾病
lots of bacterial infections
好多好多的細菌感染
Whether you are accidentally tired today
不管你今天是不小心累殘
and you have a hole in your leg
然後你腿上有一個破洞
And then accidentally turned into a bacterial infection
然後不小心化濃有細菌感染
Whether you have any bacterial infection
不管你是任何的細菌感染
I just need a little antibiotic
我只要用一點點抗生素
This wound will heal and it won't continue to thicken.
這個傷口就會好就不會繼續化濃了
I believe everyone has this experience
我相信大家都有這個經驗
what this experience brings
這個經驗帶來的是什麼
Here's some interesting news I stumbled from the internet
這是我從網路上栽入下來一些很有趣的新聞
Antibiotic Resistance Deaths from Antibiotic Resistance
抗藥性的抗生素抗藥性而死的
For example, on February 3, 2017
譬如說在2017年2月3號裡面
I'm talking about hygrobacteria
我就講到滋餓濕菌
Hungry hygrobacterium turns into a superbug
滋餓濕感菌會變成一個超級細菌
Antibiotic resistance may develop
可能會產生一個抗生素產生抗藥性
It turned out to be in 2050
原來就是在2050年的時候
Died of antibiotic resistance
抗生素抗藥現量而死了
There are about 4.7 million people in Asia
在亞洲大概有470萬人
Now that's not me too sensational
現在這不是我也很聳聽
Everyone may still live here
大家可能還住在這邊的當下
Everyone is very healthy
大家都身體都非常的健康
no cough
也沒有咳嗽
and no pain
然後也沒有病痛
So everyone thinks that the drug resistance is far away from me.
所以大家都覺得抗藥現量離我滿遠的
That's not my business
不管我的事
But it appears in all the data
但是在所有的資料裡面顯現
wait a minute i'll tell you something
等一下我會告訴你們一件
Finally I have an era
最後我有一張時代
I will tell you guys that a recent post was interesting
我會告訴你們最近發表一篇文章很有趣
your puppy
你們養的小狗
inside dog poop
狗的糞便裡面
0.6%
竟然有0.6%
Xu Xun production containing drug resistance
含有抗藥性的敘迅產生
wait a minute i'll let you know
等一下我會讓你們知道
What a terrible thing drug-resistant Xu Xun is
抗藥性的敘迅是多麼恐怖的一件事情
Although now we still have a magic medicine to cure us
雖然現在我們還有一神藥在救治我們
But will there be no magic medicine to save us in the future?
但是在以後的將來會不會沒有神藥來救我們呢
Will there be other alternatives to replace antibiotics?
會不會有其他的替代品來替代抗生素呢
This is the first question we want to ask
這是我們所想要問的第一個問題
can report to everyone
可以跟大家報告
Indiscriminate use of antimicrobial bacteria in the prelude is becoming more and more serious
序幕業亂用看上數細菌抗藥序越來越嚴重
So human beings' practical meat is centrally victimized
所以人類實用的肉品中央受害
This is an article published on the news in 2015
這是2015年所發表的一個在新聞上面所產生的
There was a funny thing when I was a kid
在我小時候有一個有趣的事量
Because when I was a child, my family had pigs
因為我小時候我家有養豬
i remember as long as i can remember
我記得在我有記憶的時候
because my father worked in a sugar factory
因為我父親是在糖廠做事
So the income from working in the sugar factory should not be very high
所以在糖廠做事的收入應該也不是非常高
So my dad helped raise the pigs
所以我爸有幫忙養豬
We have pigs next door to our house
我們家有養豬就在我們家隔壁
next to our house
就在我們家旁邊
I remember when I was a child there was a thing called Orofi
我記得小時候有一個事料叫做Orofi
Roof
Orofi
do you all know
大家都知道嗎
It can be seen that we are about the same age
可見我們年紀差不多
This Orofi is fun
這Orofi很有趣
everyone should know
大家應該都知道
Sometimes kids don't eat
小時候有時候小孩子不吃飯
or eating fatter
或是吃得比較肥比較胖
You eat Orofi big
你吃Orofi大
we were like this when we were kids
我們小時候就這樣
When I was in elementary school, sometimes my friends would say
國小的時候有時候朋友就說
You eat Orofi
你吃Orofi
Later, when I grew up, I found out
後來我長大以後我才發現
Olby is not such an interesting thing
歐爾比不是這麼有趣的事情
why olby
為什麼歐爾比呢
What about Alfa?
歐爾肥呢
It is an additive to medicated feed
它是一種含藥物飼料的添加物
At the same time, he was the section chief of Huangjianyu Drug Management Section in Ouerhui
同時在歐爾會的黃檢魚藥品管理科的科長
Xian Zhongfa pointed out
先中發指出
It is an antibiotic that has been added to the feed in low amounts for a long time
它這種長期低量添加在飼料裡面的抗生素
It is easy to make the bacteria in the intestinal tract of animals resistant to antibiotics
很容易使動物腸道裡面的細菌產生抗藥性
this troublesome one
這麻煩大的這個
It Olbi was originally created to heal
它歐爾比當初的產生其實是要治療
for the treatment of bacterial infections
因為要治療細菌感染
Because pigs stand up easily
因為豬很容易下立
It is during the pig's growth period
就是在豬的成長一段時間
it is easy to stand
它很容易下立
Then there will be a bacterial infection causing it to stand down
然後下立會有一個細菌感染造成它下立
At this time, drug-resistant bacteria will develop
那這時候就會產生了抗藥性的細菌產生
So if you are using low volume
那如果你是用低量
Then the long-term low volume has been
然後長期的低量一直在
What will be added to the feed
飼料裡面添加會造什麼
produce resistant bacteria
就會造成抗藥性的細菌產生了
The other one is the National Institutes of Health
那另外一個就是國家衛生研究院
his sui researcher
他的蘇伊人研究員
Specific Researcher also speaks
特定研究員也有講說
In fact, our animal husbandry uses antibiotics indiscriminately
其實我們的畜牧業亂用抗生素
meat safety
所引發的肉品安全
Maybe it will follow the black heart
可能會繼黑心有以後
Taiwan three
台灣三位
a big real question
一個重大實在的問題
Wait a minute and I will too
這個等一下我也會
I will also report to you
也會跟你們跟大家報告
Don't talk about Taiwan
其實不要講台灣
Let me report to everyone, I think the situation in mainland China is more troublesome than yours
跟大家報告一下我想大陸的情況比你們更麻煩
Mainland I believe they don't use antibiotics
大陸我相信他們不用抗生素
mainland pork
大陸的豬肉
Pork in mainland China until now
一直到現在大陸的豬肉
some are imported
還有些是靠進口
Because some of them raise pigs in the country
因為他們國內有些養豬的
Information on antibiotics may also be used
可能也會使用抗生素的情報
I think antibiotics are in mainland China
我想抗生素在中國大陸
in Taiwan or in Southeast Asian countries
在台灣或在東南亞國家
Cases that should abound
應該比比皆是的case
then let's talk about it
那我們再接下來講
antibiotic
抗生素的
Why These Bacteria Become Drug-Resistant
為什麼這些細菌會產生抗藥性
Because for example, this is a very simple
因為譬如說這是一張很簡單的
From a very simple graph
從一張很簡單的一個圖表
Because this bacterium if
因為這個細菌如果
If the bacteria become resistant
這個細菌如果產生抗藥性
it goes through beef cattle or pigs or chickens
它經過肉牛或豬或雞
after eating
吃進去以後
It's antibiotics, it can't kill the bacteria with the yellow dot
它這個抗生素它是沒有辦法把這個黃色點的細菌殺掉的
So this resistant bacterium
所以這個產生抗藥性的細菌
still remain in
還存留在
then it passes through feces
然後它透過糞便
if there is any food
那如果有什麼食物
You can eat it later
你們可以吃進去以後
After people step on these resolutions or implement
人踩到這些分辨或施行後
the drug-resistant bacteria with these yellow dots
就會這些黃色點的抗藥性的細菌
remain in the human body
就一直殘留在人體裡面
So what kind of impact does this have? Is it sick?
那這有什麼樣的衝擊就是生病嘛
So when a bacterial infection
所以當細菌性感染
When we humans have so-called drug-resistant bacterial infections
當我們人有所謂的抗藥性細菌感染的時候
On the back of the medical treatment on the clinical
在後面醫學上 臨床上面治療
is very tricky
是非常棘手的
Especially in doctors they have to prescribe some appropriate antibiotics
尤其在醫生他們要開一些適當的抗藥性
when appropriate antibiotics
適當的抗生素的時候
It's actually very, very tricky.
其實都是非常非常的棘手
When I want to tell you this list
那這張表我要告訴大家的時候
This is called a post-antibiotic era
這叫做一個後抗生素時代
In this book in 2013
在2013年這本書裡面
Tell us that green plum trees were born in 1928
告訴我們說1928年有青梅樹的產生
Green plum tree is actually a very interesting story
青梅樹其實也是一個很有趣的故事
The green plum tree is the stock crops raised in a pile
青梅樹是在一堆養的那個stock crops
It has a fungus that fell into it
裡面它有一個菌掉進去了
Then he found that around the fungus
然後他發現那個菌的周圍
Every bacterium is surrounded by prison
每一菌的周圍都入獄了
Then there is no inferior growth in the vicinity
然後附近都沒有遜陷成長
Then after floating for a year, I feel
然後浮來一年就覺得
it's a lot of fun
這是一個很有趣的
very interesting phenomenon
很有趣的一個現象
to develop a drug
而去開發出來一個藥物
Then we can see that from 19%
那我們可以看到從19%
From 1987 to the present, from 2011 to the present
1987年一直到現在,2011年到最近
We don't have so-called new antibiotics
我們沒有所謂新型抗生素的產生
Until 2014, 2015
直到2014、2015
There is a drug that has been approved by the US FDA
有一個藥物在美國 FDA 已經通過
Approved for marketing, recently there is another antibiotic approved for marketing
准許上市,最近還有一個抗生素准許要上市
so
所以
until so many years
一直到這麼多年
In fact, none of us have the so-called new antibiotics.
其實我們都沒有所謂新型的抗生素
The development of these antibiotics since the beginning of mankind
人類由始以來這些抗生素的發展
The period from 1928 to 1987 was the peak period of antibiotics
從1928年到1987年是抗生素的高峰時期
When humans discovered these antibiotics
在人類發現這些抗生素的時候
Antibiotics are also booming most during this time
抗生素在這一段時間也最蓬勃發展
This period of time also created the history of human health
這一段時間也就是造就了人類健康史上
best brilliant stage
最好的輝煌的階段
this stage
這段階段
As soon as any anti-suspended bacteria come out, they will be eliminated by the following drugs
一出來什麼樣的抗蕩性的菌馬上就會被後面的藥物
kill it
把它給殺掉
So you can see that in 1928, seven or eight years of antibiotics were produced, in 1945, four or five years of antibiotics were produced, and in 1979, another antibiotic was produced
所以你可以看到1928年有七、八年素的產生,1945年也四、五年素的產生,1979年有另外一種抗生素的產生
these things
這些東西
Dongying suppressed the so-called
東盈共抑制所謂的
broad-spectrum resistance
廣效性的抗藥
Antibiotic Bacteria
抗生的細菌
So what we're going to say next, this is what I just reported to you
所以我們接下來要講,這就是我剛剛跟大家報告的
In 2014, naturally...
在2014年,自然...
There is a journal called Nature Biotechnology
有一個雜誌叫做自然生物技術的雜誌
One biotechnology inside Nature, one inside a journal
自然雜誌裡面的一個生物技術,一個雜誌裡面
October 2014, it has an interesting story
2014年10月,它有談到一件有趣的故事
A description, it says US FDA
一個描述,它說美國的FDA
is what we know as the FDA
就是我們所知道的美國食品藥物管理局
It makes a drug, the drug can be approved for marketing
它讓一個藥物,這個藥物可以准許上市
This is a new type of antibiotic
這是一個新型的一個抗生素
It's presumably in IV mode, it hits the vein
它大概是用靜脈注射模式,可以打到靜脈
Then prevent some of the bacteria that MSA infects
然後預防一些MSA所感染的細菌
It's a troublesome bacterium, the bacterial infection of MSA
這是一個很麻煩的細菌,MSA的細菌感染
At the same time, a year earlier, in 2013,
那同時在早一年,2013年的時候
Someone started talking about antimicrobial status coming back
有人開始談到抗菌態是不是會回來了
Should we be looking for a new anti...
我們是不是應該要尋找一個新的抗...
an antibacterial substance other than antibiotics
有別於抗生素的一個抗菌的物質
So in the 2013 Nature Journal of Biotechnology in the Nature Journal
所以在2013年的自然雜誌裡面的生物技術的自然雜誌裡面
He mentioned a report that said
他有談到一個報導就是說
Antibacterial
是不是應該把抗菌態
Come back and do some research
再重新回來好好地研究一下
Is it possible as a new type of
是不是有可能當作一個新型的
new antimicrobial substances
新型的抗菌物質
Therefore, the antibacterial state research has probably been
所以抗菌態研究到現在大概有
twenty years, twenty or thirty years
二十幾年、二三十年
Probably more intensive research
大概比較密集的研究
There are now more than 350,000 papers
現在有三十五萬篇以上的論文
are published in some related journals
都發表在一些相關的期刊
so we feel
所以我們覺得
We just reported to you
我們剛剛跟大家報告
there are many struggles
就是有很多的抗爭數
the consequences of the impact
所造成的影響的後果
leads us to want to find a new
導致我們想要找一個新的
substance that replaces the number of struggles
取代抗爭數的物質
Otherwise, there will be no medicine for human beings in the future
要不然人類將來會沒有藥物可以醫治
when there is no medical treatment
在沒有藥物醫治的時候
And with that comes a lot of death
伴隨著就是什麼大量的死亡
as the epic of yan said
就像從嚴史詩所講的
Birth of the Black Death
黑死病的產生
on top of some of the history we know
在我們所知道的一些歷史的上面
Alright, so we're going to report to you
好啦,所以我們來跟大家報告
what is antibacterial state
什麼叫做抗菌態
The origin of the antibacterial state is actually what I just reported to you
抗菌態的起源其實我剛剛有跟大家報告
In 1928, the so-called panlucillin was produced
1928年有所謂的潘律西林的產生
In 1939 there was the so-called
1939年有所謂的
Production of short-susceptible bacterium
短感菌態的產生
In the 1950s, everyone had the so-called anti-halo
1950年代的時候,大家有所謂的抗暈態的
Some people began to discover the so-called anti-halo state
開始有人發現所謂的抗暈態
So far we probably know
一直到目前我們大概知道
Antibiotics that may appear to be able to replace antibiotics
抗暈態它可以似乎能夠取代抗生素
is able to serve as a cancer treatment drug
是能夠來端做一個癌症治療藥物
The latest research results
目前最新的研究結果
we haven't
我們還沒有
We only have some verification on the so-called animal experiments
我們只有在所謂的動物實驗上面有一些驗證
But we believe in the future of halo resistance
但是我們相信抗暈態將來
Appears to be a replacement for antibiotics
似乎可以當作一個取代抗生素
a new substance
一個新興的一個物質
Next I will talk about some of our laboratory
接下來我會講一些我們實驗室的
Report the results of the research and development
所研發的成果,向各位報告一下
Why Antisickness Could Be an Emerging Drug in the Future
為什麼抗暈態可以將來當作一個新興的藥物
Why anti-halostates have the power to replace antibiotics
為什麼抗暈態有能力取代抗生素
Why anti-halostate may be used as an emerging anti-cancer drug in the future
為什麼抗暈態將來可以當作一個新興的抗癌藥物
you probably don't know
你們大概大家有所不知
One of the newest emerging cancer drugs is called PDL1
現在最新興的一個抗癌藥物叫做PDL1
PDL1 I just recently found out
PDL1我最近我才知道
it is a very expensive drug
它是一個非常昂貴的藥物
A course of treatment should be done 24 times
一個療程要做24次
For each course of treatment, do you want to guess how many times it has?
每一次的療程大家要不要猜猜看它有多少次
244 after a course of treatment
整個244一個療程以後
you probably know
你們大概知道
PDL1 this latest
PDL1這個最新的
anticancer drugs
抗癌的藥物
Do you know how much it costs?
你們知道要多少錢嗎?
Nope
沒有耶
I only recently found out
我最近才知道
3000000
300萬
right
對
I
我
I'm scared to death
我嚇死了
I was scared to death when I heard that number
我聽到這個數字的時候我嚇死了
so why do we want
所以為什麼我們想要
Want to find an up-to-date drug production
想要尋找一個最新的藥物產生
just hope we will
就希望我們將來
we can in taiwan
我們能夠在台灣
find out find out from deep water creatures
找出從水深生物裡面找出
Our own Niche in Taiwan
我們自己在台灣的Niche
You see, Taiwan is surrounded by the sea
你看台灣四面環海
So Taiwan's marine biotechnology research
所以台灣的海洋生物科技的研究
Won't
不會
will not alienate other countries
不會疏離其他的國家
We should pay more attention to the marine life
我們更應該要注重從海洋生物裡面
get the natural resources we need
得到我們所需要的自然資源
then later
那後來
Transform back to what we want to introduce to you
化轉回來我們要跟大家介紹一下什麼
anti-pregnancy
叫做抗孕胎
Anti-pregnancy is actually basically it
抗孕胎其實是基本上它
Probably divided into several types in terms of shape
大概在型態上有分成幾種的類型
Then its type has the so-called spiral
那它的類型有所謂的螺旋狀的
Or a shape similar to a board
或是一接類似博板的形狀
or a shape with specific amino acids
或是有特殊胺基酸的一個形狀
That's one of the anti-rhyme patterns we listed.
那這是我們所列的一個抗韻胎的模式
That anti-rhyme, it will have plants and animals in all animals
那抗韻胎它在所有的動物體裡面都會有植物動物
including in your body
包括你的身體裡面也有
The human body also has the so-called anti-rhyme fetus
人類的身體裡面也有所謂的抗韻胎
There is a so-called anti-rhyme tire in the body of the fish
那魚的身體裡面有所謂抗韻胎
The anti-rhyme substance is like the eggs you have eaten
抗韻胎的物質就像你們吃過的雞蛋一樣
You all know that eggs contain a lot of protein, right?
雞蛋你們都知道裡面有很多大量的蛋白質對不對
But the ecology is relatively small
但是生態是比較小的
small molecules smaller than proteins
小的分子比蛋白質更小一點的分子
Only about 20 amino acids to 50 amino acids
大概只有20個胺基酸到50個胺基酸
Smaller anti-rhyme tires are now reported
更小的抗韻胎以現在所報導
About 5 to 10 amino acids have antibacterial ability
大概5到10個胺基酸就有具有抗菌的能力
So our family just reported that
所以我們家剛剛大報告就是說
Anti-rhyme tires actually exist in all nature
抗韻胎其實在所有的自然界裡面都有
Including puppies and cats in your home
包括你們家裡面養的小狗小貓
piggy too
小豬也有
Okay, let's also tell you about anti-rhythm tires, which can kill a lot of bacteria.
好 那我們也跟大家講抗韻胎它可以殺了很多細菌
It can be verified experimentally
可以它居然的實驗驗證
Anti rhyme can kill bacteria
抗韻胎可以殺細菌
Needles, protozoa, and cancer
針菌、原生動物病毒還有癌症
It can also have what is called immune regulation
它還可以有什麼所謂的免疫調控
wait a minute i tell you
等一下我告訴你們
You all may not know one thing
你們大家或許不知道一件事
maybe know something
或許知道一件事
when we catch a cold
當我們感冒
When we have a bacterial infection when we are injured
當我們受傷的時候有細菌感染的時候
you will hurt, right?
你們會痛對不對
Will everyone be in pain?
大家會很痛苦嘛
like sometimes when my mother is sick
像有時候我母親生病的時候就
very painful
非常的痛
Tell me every day that she has back pain
就每天跟我說她腰酸背痛
or which side hurts
或是哪邊痛
do you know why it hurts
你們知道為什麼會疼痛嗎
Pain is due to bacterial infection
疼痛是因為細菌感染以後
Cause immune inflammation, increase immune factors
造成免疫發炎、免疫因子的提升
but you know
但是你們知道
you bring
你們帶
Sometimes we most often hear a sentence that is
有時候我們最常聽到一句話就是
The child goes to the hospital
小孩子到醫院裡面去
what is a good doctor
什麼叫做好的醫生
A good doctor is to prevent children from crying
好的醫生就是讓小孩子不會哭提提的
Take an iron medicine now
馬上吃一鐵藥
take medicine for a day
吃一天的藥
The grandson won't cry if he hugs him back
孫子抱回去就不會哭了
Then grandpa and grandma said
然後阿公阿嬤就說
this doctor give me doctor
這醫生給我醫生
so that's not going to be good
所以那都不會好
is it interesting
有趣嗎
yes it's interesting let me tell you
對好有趣我跟你們講
now have some medicine
現在有一些藥
so-called steroids
是所謂的類固醇
What are steroid drugs for?
類固醇藥物是幹嘛?
some steroid medicines
有些類固醇藥物
It suppresses your immune inflammatory response
它可以抑制你們的免疫發炎反應
when our human body
當我們的人的身體的時候
When we humans suffer from bacterial infection
我們人在遭受細菌感染的時候
The most likely to happen is the immune system
最容易發生的就是免疫的系統
it will start to raise
它會開始提升
The immune system seems to have some immune genes
免疫系統好像有些免疫基因
Will be sequenced to produce some cytokines
會被次序產生一些細胞激素也好
or the production of immune factors
或是免疫因子的產生
It's time to induce your body
它這時候是為了要誘導你的身體
giant cells or intermediate leukocytes
巨式細胞或是市中間白血球
to phagocytize the bacteria washed in
去吞噬清洗進來的細菌
But sometimes a good doctor
但是這時候有時候好醫生
Of course, there are fewer such good doctors now.
當然現在這個好醫生比較少
I guess again
我再猜
But because of the request of the family
但是因為家屬的要求
Grandpa and grandma's request or parent's request
阿公阿嬤的要求或是家長的要求
Said that today I grow very thin
說這一天我長得很瘦
i slept all day in my sister ok
我睡了一整天都在妹妹好
This doctor is better
這醫生比較好
After taking the medicine for a day, my sister will not be well
吃了一天藥就不會妹妹好
so this doctor is good
所以這醫生好
He gave you some steroids
他就開了一些類固醇給你們
Steroids reduce pain
類固醇會降低疼痛
it's very good, but i feel like i have to say
它非常好的,但是我覺得我也要講
Steroids are the magic drug I've known since
類固醇是由此以來我所認識的神藥
other than antibiotics
除了抗生素以外
it keeps you from pain
它讓你不會很疼痛
Then do you know that every system is reduced
那你們知不知道每一系統一降低
For example, when your original bacteria are cleaned
譬如說你們的本來細菌清洗的時候
There are giant bubbles with four intermediate white bacteria
有巨式氣泡有四中間白菌
It's going to devour the bacteria in your light body
它去吞噬你們的輕入身裡面的細菌
As a result, each system has a reduced
結果每一系統一降低了
it suppresses your immunity
它把你的免疫壓下來
What does that bring?
那帶到什麼?
what about these bacteria
這些細菌呢
flourishing
蓬勃的發展
Because there is no army to kill these bacteria
因為沒有軍隊去把這些細菌給殺掉
that without killing
那在沒有殺掉的情況之下
Bacteria are of course happy to produce
細菌當然就很高興的產生
Then the doctor will definitely use
那這時候醫生一定會用在
How many things are prescribed in your medicine
你們的藥裡面開了幾樣東西
antibiotic
抗生素
It's two sides of the same thing, right?
是一體兩面的嘛對不對
You have suppressed your immunity
你壓了免疫力壓下來
Bacteria proliferate
細菌大量產生
Then this person won't hang you up
那這人不掛掉你們
You say it's possible or impossible?
你們說有可能啊不可能嘛
when bacteria are about to go up
當細菌要上去的時候
It gives you antibiotics to kill the bacteria
它就給你抗生素讓你去殺的細菌
So basically in many drugs
所以基本上在很多的藥物裡面
The doctor will prescribe these two drugs together
醫生會一起開這兩種藥物給你們
Let you not be in pain and get well again
讓你們不會痛然後又病好
so it's a vicious cycle
所以這就是惡性循環
Begins to generate endless nightmares
開始產生無止境的惡夢產生
I want to report to everyone that is
我要跟大家報告就是說
fighting it has an advantage
抗爭它有一個好處
It inhibits the production of some inflammatory factors
它會抑制一些發炎因子的產生
So it has what's called immune regulation
所以它有所謂的免疫調控
But it also has the ability to kill bacteria
但是它也有殺菌的能力
Unlike what I just reported to you
不像剛剛我跟大家報告的
You must take two medicines
你們必須吃兩種藥
Now if it can really become medicine
現在如果真的能變成藥
You only need to eat one
你們只要吃一種
wait a minute you will ask me
等一下你們一定會問我
Is there any resistance to anti-morbidity?
抗病態有沒有抗藥性
i will tell you
我會跟你們講
Is there a question of drug resistance?
有沒有抗藥性這個問題
So everyone should be curious and ask me
所以大家也要好奇的問我說
until now
一直到現在
Has the world's anti-morbidity been made into medicine?
全世界抗病態到底做成藥了嗎
Because I saw someone on B said
因為我在B上面看到有人說
Has this medicine come out?
這個藥到底有沒有出來
Is there any medicine
有沒有做成藥
Who is this shoot
這拍誰
There is not yet any anti-morbid drug
現在還沒有任何一個抗病態的藥
have been used clinically
有在臨床上被使用
be industrialized commercialized
被產業化 商業化
but there are many drugs
但是有很多的藥物
Has entered clinical phase II or III
已經進到臨床二期或三期了
even like this drug is done
甚至像這個藥物是已經做完了
That's for diabetes
那這個是治療糖尿病
What about diabetic patients?
糖尿病的病人呢
he sometimes has wounds
他有時候會有傷口
big wound
很大的傷口
Because everyone is still full
因為大家還吃飽飯
So I'm sticking that picture over here
所以我把那個圖片往指貼在這邊
Everyone is interested to see
大家有興趣再去看
i don't want to put that picture
我不想放那個圖片
Wait a minute everyone is throwing up over here
等一下大家在這邊吐了
What about the other one?
那另外一個就是說呢
and catheter
還有導尿管
You may not have experience
大家可能沒有經驗
It hurts to eat that catheter
那個導尿管吃進去很痛
But sometimes when the catheter is full, the urine bag comes out
但是導尿管有時候尿袋滿出來的時候
when urine flushes back
尿又回沖的時候
It's easy to get bacteria over there
那邊很容易感染細菌
So what about the catheter thing?
所以導尿管它的東西呢
Many people have been making anti-smoke soup
一直是很多在做抗菸湯
and then do some
然後在上面做一些
in some
在一些
put some anti-smoke soup on the catheter
在放一些抗菸湯在導尿管上
make it sterilizable
讓它可以殺菌
Candida infection
還有念珠菌的感染
for example
譬如說
sometimes
有時候呢
Your mouth and tongue will be white
你們嘴巴舌頭會有白白一層
that resembles a bacterial infection
那類似曾菌感染
Then everyone can brush it out with any toothbrush
然後大家不是哪牙刷就能刷出來
mouth smelly today
今天嘴巴臭臭的
Because the teeth are not brushed well
因為牙齒沒刷好
But in fact, after brushing it ten times and twenty times, it still smells bad.
但是其實刷了十遍二十遍還是很臭
because there is no mobile phone
因為沒有手臺
It's sort of a pregnancy infection because the white layer is over there
它有些是增孕感染,因為白白一層在那邊
This is the so-called roller fungus infection, so some people put the anti-smoke form in the empty water for brushing their teeth before doing research and development.
這是所謂的碾珠菌感染,所以也有人把抗菸態放在刷牙宿空水裡面再做研發
All kinds of these anti-smoke states are in the data we compiled in 2015, we probably know that there are these anti-smoke states
種種的這些抗菸態在我們2015年所整理的資料裡面,我們大概知道有這些抗菸態
Has entered clinical phase II and phase III or has even ended
已經進入到臨床二期三期或甚至已經結束了
I was in our firm last year, and every year there are so-called PI speeches in our firm
我去年在我們所裡面,每一年我們所裡面都有所謂的PI演講
I will talk to us about the report in the same text. The research I did is that Sus mother has been herding sheep for 18 years.
我就跟我們說面同文報告,我做的研究是蘇母牧羊18年
Why shepherd sheep for 18 years, I will report to all of you later
為什麼要牧羊18年,等一下跟你們大家報告
Like this drug is 1998 in Joc this drug, this drug is this drug
像這個藥物是1998年在Joc這個藥物,這個藥物是這個藥物
A drug from this company
這家公司出來的一個藥物
it uses an anti-smoke form as a drug
它是使用一個抗菸態來做藥物
Since it published this magazine in 1998
那它1998年發表這篇雜誌以來
everyone can see
大家可以看到
until October 25, 2016
到2016年的10月25號
US APPDA
美國APPDA
It actually failed the clinical phase III test, because the US APPDA felt that its
它竟然沒有通過臨床三期的測試,因為美國APPDA覺得它的
The results of its measurements are not hot for the present
它的測量的結果並沒有對現在的燒燙
Existing drugs for trauma have better outcomes
就是創傷現有的藥物有更好的結果
more meaningful difference
更有意義的差異性
So the DA in the United States rejected the drug body
所以美國的DA把這個藥物的身體給否決掉了
I told our comrades
我就跟我們同志說
It has been herding for 19 years
它牧了19年了
I may have to keep me like this for more than 20 years
我可能要牧我20幾年這樣子
Because foreign funds may be more abundant
因為國外資金可能比較充沛
We are in Taiwan and I have been looking for a pharmaceutical factory to cooperate with
我們在台灣我一直都在找有沒有合作的藥廠
Come and help us herd the sheep
可以來協助我們牧羊一下
Then this chance of shepherding still hopes to have a chance in the future
那這牧羊的機會還是希望將來有機會
You can treat the whole world based on Taiwan
可以立足台灣救治全世界這樣
I've been lecturing to Pops, the student council assistant in our lab,
我一直跟我們實驗室的學生會助理Pops大講
We are in Xiaosuo Taiwan
我們在小所台灣
we want something like
我們要像類似一樣
When everyone talks about similarities, they talk about old similarities
大家講到類似就講到老類似
speaking of chocolate
講到巧克力
in such a small country
這麼一個小的國家裡面
How can it develop such a famous thing
它憑什麼可以發展那麼有名的東西
So we're doing research in the little territorial waters
所以我們就是在小小的領海研究在裡面
We want to be able to make a world that can
我們希望能夠做出一個全世界都能夠
a thing used
用到的一個東西
let me tell you now
那現在來跟大家講一下
antibacterial tire
抗菌胎呢
what does it look like
它有什麼樣子的
can let
可以讓
Does not develop resistance like antibiotics
不會類似抗生素一樣產生抗藥性
This is a very important feature
這是一個很重要的特點
no antibiotics
抗生素沒有的
antibacterial tire
抗菌胎呢
it will have so-called
它會有所謂的
that
那個
A break in the groove
穿槽的一個打破
A Mechanism for Breaking Bacterial Cell Membranes
打破細菌細胞B or細胞膜的一個機制
For example it has what's called a vat side panel pattern
譬如說它有所謂的大桶側板的模式
This is antibacterial tire
這是抗菌胎
It is antibacterial on the surface of bacterial cell B or cell membrane
它抗菌胎在細菌細胞B或細胞膜上面
It will utilize a schema like this big bucket
它會利用類似這樣大桶的模式
Then insert it into the bacterial cell B or above the cell membrane
然後插進去細菌的細胞B或細胞膜上面
become a hole
變成一個洞
Then the contents of the bacteria will flow out
然後細菌的內容物就會流出來
Then the bacteria die
然後細菌就掛了
The other is the carpet pattern
另外一個是地毯的模式
I can only talk about these two very simple modes today
我今天只有講這兩種很簡單的模式
Then these two modes will let the bacteria hang
那這兩種模式就會讓細菌掛了
It's going to be a lot of fun on the web
這在網路上會有一個很有趣的
very interesting video
很有趣的影片
I'll let everyone take a look
我讓大家看一下
because
因為呢
this
這個
This is the one on YouTube
這個是 YouTube 上面的一個
an interesting Data
一個有趣的 Data
You can see it's bacteria
你們可以看到這是細菌
Then it starts to be antibacterial on the connection
那它開始上面有被抗菌在連接上
It will break the chain, break the determination, break some troubles
它就會斷開鎖鏈、斷開篤決、斷開一些煩惱
burst the bacteria
把細菌給撐破了
You can see this green thing forming a hole
你可以看到這綠色的東西形成一個孔洞
Then the bacteria stuff comes out
然後細菌的東西就流出去了
Then the bacteria disintegrates
然後這個細菌就瓦解了
these disintegrating things
這些瓦解的東西
Bacteria will no longer increase in value
細菌它就不會再增值
no more harm to the human body
也不會再傷害人體
So after we finish talking about this
所以我們把這個東西講完以後
Everyone must be curious and ask me
大家一定很好奇的問我
Teacher Chen, just now I was wondering if you are doing well
陳老師,剛請問你有沒有好厲害
Let's look at the next
我們來看下面一個
This is the hospital cooperation published by PNS in 2014
這是PNS2014年發表醫院配合
You can see it when doing PM
你可以看到它在做PM的時候
electron microscope
就電子顯微鏡
You can see this is a beautiful bacillus
可以看到這個是很漂亮的桿菌
Bacillus it passes through an antibacterial tire
桿菌它經過一個抗菌胎
It's called C3A, use 0.3 micron
叫C3A,用0.3微末的東西
It can burst the bacteria
它就可以把細菌給撐破了
This is what a Streptococcus pneumoniae does in our lab
這就是在我們實驗室所做的一個肺炎鏈球菌
You can see that pneumococcus is beautiful
你可以看到肺炎鏈球菌好漂亮
like a basketball
像一顆籃球一樣
We also see these bacteria
我們也是看到這些細菌
I really think the recruiter is really good at recruiting
我真的覺得招募者真的是招得太漂亮了
This is handsome eyebrow feather
這個是俊男眉羽
The handsome eyebrows in this bacteria
這細菌裡面的俊男眉羽
But many doctors in infection department saw this
但是有很多感染科的醫生看到這個
Everyone is scared to death
大家嚇死了這樣子
How could so much of this thing be detected in the patient's blood
怎麼會這麼多這個東西在病人的血液裡面被檢測出來
After we added the antibacterial status of the grouper
我們添加了石斑魚的抗菌態以後
You can see the bacteria disintegrate all over it
你可以看到它細菌整個都瓦解掉了
This is the result of an experiment we did in 2005
這是在我們2005年所做的一個實驗結果
Streptococcus pneumoniae is a troublesome disease
肺炎鏈球菌它是一個很麻煩的疾病
another one
另外一個
This is the so-called vaginal petting
這是所謂的陰道低寵
This is a gene bank bought vagina low pet bought by ATCC
這是ATCC買來的一個基因庫買來的陰道低寵
This is a low favor of the vagina obtained from the clinic
這是從臨床上面得到的一個陰道低寵
Vaginal low pampering can cause many unpleasant ailments for the wealthy
陰道低寵會引起很多富裕的不愉快的疾病
If we put antibacterial status together with these vagina pets
我們如果把抗菌態跟這些陰道低寵放在一起
You can see that this treatment of the grouper just talked to it
你可以看到這次處理石斑魚剛跟它講
1 in 10 is disease-resistant
十分之一能夠抗病態
We fight disease by using ecosynthesis
我們抗病態是用生態合成
The anti-pathological effect of a synthesized section of twenty-one amino acid
以合成出來的一段二十一個胺劑酸的抗病態
instead of putting the whole fish down
不是把整隻魚放下去
Don't get me wrong
大家不要誤解
After we put this synthetic anti-morbidity in
我們把這個合成的抗病態放進去以後
You can see nine hundred and sixty minutes later
你可以看到九百六十分鐘以後
The whole bacteria is disintegrated
整個細菌都瓦解掉了
This is the anti-morbidity obtained from the shrimp
這是從蝦子上面得到的抗病態
It also has the same function
它也具有同樣的功能
Why Vaginal Lows Are Trouble Doing
為什麼陰道低重做的麻煩
because it has a tick on the side
因為它有一個勾勾在這邊
It hooks the cell surface of the vaginal epithelium
它會勾住了陰道上皮的細胞表層
So the disease will be cleaned repeatedly
所以這個疾病會反覆的不斷的清洗
Also because of its low vaginal weight, it has so-called drug resistance
也因為它陰道低重有所謂的抗藥性
Many diseases are like flu
很多的疾病就是類似感冒一樣
ate it now the drug is a so-called
吃了它現在藥物是用所謂的一個
Metadolol Anti-Correction into Coatings
抗成塗料的Metadolol來治療
After treatment it will become a negative recurrence
治療以後它會成負的再犯
well , we can know anti - pathological
好,我們可以知道抗病態
it kills these germs or something
它可以殺了這些細菌或是一些東西
This is what I just reported to you
這是我剛剛跟大家報的
anti-pathological it has the ability to inhibit some
抗病態它具有抑制一些
suppression of immune inflammation
免疫發炎的抑制
an effect of a factor
因子的一個作用
Let's take a look
我們稍微看過去就好了
It TLR method is a
它TLR法是一個
It is a factor of inflammation immunity
它是一個就是一個發炎免疫的一個因子
When the car reaches this factor in the body
當身體裡面如果車到這個因子
When this cell technology is manifested in large quantities
這個細胞技術大量表現的時候
It's kind of like an inflammation in the body.
就有一點類似身體裡面發炎了
That's when I just said
那這時候就是我剛剛講
steroids or other drugs
類固醇或是其他的藥物
it can suppress this
它可以把這個抑制下來
The same antibacterial state can also inhibit it
那同樣的抗菌態也可以把它抑制下來
what's the other interesting thing
那另外一個有趣的事是什麼呢
Antibacterial state it can act like an antibiotic
抗菌態它可以類似抗生素一樣
Many antibiotics go into bacteria
很多的抗生素它都是到細菌的裡面
It inhibits DNA to RNA
它會抑制DNA到RNA
or RNA into the process of protein synthesis
或RNA到蛋白質合成的過程裡面
The same antibacterial state will
同樣的抗菌態也會
In 2011 this magazine told us that
在2011年這篇雜誌裡面有告訴我們說
Antibacterial states There are many different antibacterial states
抗菌態這邊有很多不同的抗菌態
For example, let me take one
譬如說我舉一個
Here's an antibacterial state from that flounder
這是從那個比目魚上面所得到的一個抗菌態
This antibacterial state it can inhibit DNA to protein
這抗菌態它可以抑制DNA到蛋白質
Bacterial DNA to protein synthesis
細菌的DNA到蛋白質合成
So now there are some studies from here
所以由這邊現在目前也有一些研究
Reporting Research in the Lab
報告在實驗室裡面的研究
Tell us that the antimicrobial state has the potential to develop resistance
告訴我們說抗菌態有可能產生抗藥性
Currently there are some reports telling us
目前有一些報告告訴我們
But it's all so-called artificially made in the laboratory.
但是都是所謂的人工在實驗室裡面做出來
The so-called drug resistance has not been obtained in nature
還沒有在自然界裡面得到所謂的抗藥性
antimicrobial resistance of a bacterium
抗抗菌態的抗藥性的一個細菌
Then I will report another phenomenon to you next.
那我接下來再跟大家報告一個現象
Just now everyone will see what I just said
剛剛大家都會看到我剛剛有講
Bacterial infection will eventually cause what systemic
細菌感染最後會引發什麼全身性的
syndrome of inflammatory response
發炎反應的症候群
so-called sepsis
就所謂的敗血症
Then many times the virus you are in the hospital
那很多時候病毒你在醫院裡面
You will all know the so-called sepsis
你們大家都會知道所謂的敗血症
The source of many of his infections is mostly bacteria.
很多他的感染源多半都是細菌
It may also be caused by fungal viruses or gauges to produce mild in vivo
那也可能會被黴菌病毒或計生成輕度體內
causing sepsis
而引發敗血
That sepsis is very troublesome, that is to say
那敗血很麻煩的就是說
The trouble now is to say
現在很麻煩的就是說
When he screened out some kind of resistant bacteria
當他篩出來是某種抗藥性的細菌的時候
When there were no antibiotics to treat
以前沒有抗生素可以治療的時候
This is the most troublesome place
這時候就是最麻煩的地方
He would treat patients with different antibiotics over and over again.
他就會一再的用不同的抗生素來治療病人
Of course there's no way it's going to cause what's called lung congestion.
當然就沒有辦法會引起所謂的肺部充血
then cause death
然後引起死亡
What about the anti... this sepsis?
那這個抗...這個敗血症呢
What about sepsis?
其實敗血症呢
Approximately 30% mortality
大概可以達到30%的死亡率
Then the mortality rate of severe sepsis is about 50%.
然後重度的敗血症死亡率大概有50%
Of course it varies with age.
那當然是隨著不同的年紀啊
Sepsis Caused by Different Ethnic Groups and Different Regions
不同的族群、不同的區域所造成的敗血症
while the death rate varies
而死亡率有所不同
we must tell you now
我們現在必須告訴你們說
This... is the current treatment in medicine
這...就在目前在醫學上面的治療
that's what i just told you
就是我剛剛跟大家講的
anticancer drugs
就是使用抗癌素
What about the anticancer drug?
那這抗癌素呢
also... it inhibits the growth of bacteria
也有所...它會抑制細菌的成長
that would also use some so-called intellectual healing
那也會使用一些所謂的知識性的治療
For example, steroid suppression...
譬如說內固醇抑制...
Steroids suppress immunity
內固醇會抑制免疫力
then will...
然後會...
But what about the steroids?
但是這個內固醇呢
It enhances the growth of bacteria
它會增益細菌的成長
So when the two drugs alternate
所以在這兩種藥物的交替的時候呢
It is currently a treatment for sepsis...
是目前治療敗血症的一個...
a very important step
一個很重要的一個步驟
I will introduce our protagonist today
我今天先介紹我們的主角
The main character is called...
這主角叫做...
There was just a talk called Ibsidium 1
剛剛有講叫做Ibsidium 1
What about this anti-electric titanium?
那這個抗電鈦呢
I got it from Spotted Grouper back then
是當初我從點帶石斑裡面得到的
Everyone must not know how to call it a little grouper
大家一定不知道怎麼叫點帶石斑
It's all grouper anyway.
反正都是石斑魚
Because hairtail is now divided into
因為點帶魚現在分成
Grouper is now divided into dragon belly grouper
石斑魚現在分成龍腩石斑
What about dragon and tiger spots?
點帶石斑還有什麼龍虎斑
I actually can't figure it out myself
我事實上我自己也搞不清楚
Got a lot of different groupers
搞了好多不同的石斑魚
Anyway, the tastiest one is the dragon and tiger stripes.
反正最好吃的就是龍虎斑
This should be
應該是這樣
Then in the process of eating fish
那大家吃魚的過程裡面
Everyone will think of something
大家一定會想到一件有事
You've killed fish, haven't you?
你們有殺過魚吧對不對
there may be some people who haven't killed fish
可能有些人沒有殺過魚
That fish will be slippery, right?
那魚會滑滑的對不對
you know fish can be slippery
你們知道魚會滑滑的
Then you know that in that year's luck
那你們知道在那年運裡面
Is there antistatic titanium?
有抗電鈦嗎
may not know
可能不知道
I told you in the grouper
我跟你們講在石斑裡面
Some Lucky Years contain anti-electric titanium
那有些年運裡面是有抗電鈦的
very interesting
挺有趣的
why are you so funny
為什麼你這麼有趣
You think about our life I am in this air
你們想想我們人生我在這個空氣裡面
The one in Beijing is PM2.5, right?
北京的那個買是PM2.5對不對
There is no news recently
最近不是有新聞說
There is so-called anti-glory news in Beijing's shopping
北京的買裡面有所謂的抗耀性的消息
Bury it there?
在那埋上面嗎?
then think about it
那你想想
When we were kids we were fishing
小時候我們在釣魚的時候
when catching fish
抓魚的時候
People say that if the water is clear, there will be no fish
人家說水清則無魚
The water needs to be nourished by Pia
水要滋裸的靠皮亞
There are many things in naked
滋裸的就有很多東西
a lot of sand
沙子很多
a lot of bacteria
細菌量很多
so the water is naked
所以水就很裸
when naked
裸的時候
Think about why you can grow up in such a naked environment
你想想你為什麼可以在這麼裸的環境裡面長大
How good it is to grow fat and fat
還可以長得肥肥又胖胖多好
That means its body is in the process of evolution
那代表它的身體在演化的過程裡面
Is there a special mechanism evolved?
是不是有演化出一個特殊的機制
What is the mechanism of sterilization?
產生殺菌的機制呢?
ok
好啦
So I'm here to report
所以我來跟大家報告一下
The stone pound fish has an antibacterial
石磅魚上面有一個抗菌
It's called IPSYN1
它叫IPSYN1
Then this probably
那這個大概
We are currently in the laboratory
我們就在目前在實驗室
what we do antibacterial
我們所做的抗菌
It's about 21 MG acid
它大概是21個MG酸
Then it is the so-called sheep nose with double skin
那它是所謂的羊鼻子有雙皮性的
It is the difference between the so-called clear water and crisp water
就是它有所謂的清水跟酥水性的一個不同的
an ecology
一個生態
Then we are at IPSYN1
那我們就在IPSYN1
in our laboratory
在我們實驗室裡面
We have fought against swelling in the sentinel cabin
我們已經針對哨艙傷抗腫
Some netizens watched biological disease resistance
有看網民生物抗病
I'm still immune and we're done.
我還有免疫條件我們都做完了
Then this is just a cute stone pound fish
那這一隻是很可愛的石磅魚
There are also a lot of stone pound fish industries in Taichung
石磅魚產業現在在台中也是非常多
The other one is turtle fish, I want to report to you today
那另外的是烏龜魚,我今天要跟大家報告一下
This is the Pasidium IV of the turtle fish
這個是烏龜魚的Pasidium IV
Then it comes from the so-called butter and turtle fish
那它是從所謂的牛油和烏龜魚上面來的
Then we synthesize 25 amino acids in the laboratory
那我們在實驗室裡面我們合成25個胺基酸
What about the 25 amino acids, we have already done it in the laboratory
那這個25個胺基酸呢,我們已經在實驗室裡面
It is already known that it has antibacterial and anti-swelling effects
已經知道它有抗菌,也有抗腫油的過程
I will report to you next time
接下來跟大家報告一下
The antibacterial ecology of Epsidium IV How do we do its biological activity
Epsidium IV的抗菌生態我們來怎麼來做它的生物活性
An interesting one, here I probably consist of these few
一個有趣的,這裡面我大概由這幾個
Report the results of several experiments
幾個實驗的結果跟大家報告
One is the infection of Helicobacter pylori infection, and the other is the infection of MSA
一個是幽門螺旋感染的感染,另外一個是MSA的感染
Then let's look at the infection of Helicobacter pylori infection first
那我們接下來先看幽門螺旋感染的感染
Everyone must, more or less I think
大家一定,多多少少我想
About 70% to 80% of the population in mainland China has Helicobacter pylori infection
中國大陸大概有七、八十%的人口有幽門螺旋感染的感染
In Taiwan, I believe that there should be more than 40 to 50% of people who have had it
台灣我相信,應該是有四、五十%以上有人有得過
Have had an infection without Helicobacter pylori infection in a lifetime
一輩子裡面有得過未幽門螺旋感染的感染
Then this is a beautiful bacterium again, every time I see this bacterium I get excited
那這個又是很漂亮的細菌,我每次看到這細菌我都很興奮
do you think it looks beautiful
你有沒有覺得它長得很漂亮
beautiful isn't it
很漂亮是不是
This bacterium has a lot of braided hairs that look like aliens
這細菌就是有很多編毛好像異形一樣
can grasp the gastric mucosa
可以抓住胃黏膜
For a kid, a high school student should feel bad after seeing this
對小朋友這高中生看到這個應該還覺得不怎麼樣
But after you watch Alien
但是以後你們看過異形以後
I remember the first time in my life I watched a movie about a bunch of aliens called Liquid Ladder
我記得我人生第一次看一堆外星人的片子叫液梯
I don't know if you've ever seen a liquid ladder
我不知道你們有看過液梯
have a thumb sticking out
有一個大拇指伸出來
you know like its a thumb
你知道好像它的大拇指一樣
Okay, gastric Helicobacter pylori
好啦 胃幽門螺旋桿菌
It is indeed a negative bacteria
它是果然是陰性菌
a bacterium of its tiny oxygen
它微細氧的一個細菌
The troublesome problem is gastric Helicobacter pylori
麻煩的問題是胃幽門螺旋桿菌
if you don't narrow it down
如果不窄掉它的話
It may cause ulcers and stomach cancer in the future
液梯它將來可能會導致潰瘍跟胃癌
That's probably more than 80% of the generation
那大概有超過80%的代元者
will not reveal any patients
不會顯露任何病人
that you will not hurt
就是你不會痛
I won't feel my heart
也不會有感覺到耳心
I won't feel like hitting anything
也不會感覺到打個什麼的
neither will be fun
都不會 很有趣
Then it has about 4 to 6 braids
那它大概有4到6個編毛
who discovered Helicobacter eubacterium
發現優門螺旋桿菌的人
Get someone if you can talk
拿到人如果有講得住
it was obtained by two scientists
它是有兩個科學家所得到的
This one is very simple to tell you
這一張很簡單的跟大家講
just if you got
就是如果你得到了
Because of our Helicobacter infection
因為我們螺旋桿菌的感染
what will happen
也會得到什麼結果
One is to sell into Wei Yan
一個就是賣進衛炎
The other one is to sell the shrunken Wei Yan
另外一個是賣進萎縮的衛炎
Then his writing has been deformed.
那他的上筆都已經變形了
Another duodenal ulcer
另外一個是十二指腸潰瘍
In the end, the most troublesome thing is cancer
最後最麻煩就是衛癌
Cancer is really troublesome
衛癌真的很麻煩
So what is currently the only cure for graceful idol infection?
那目前只有什麼可以治療優美的偶像感染呢?
called antibiotics
叫做抗生素
Everyone went to the hospital to finish the Wei Jing
大家去醫院照完衛精
The doctor said
醫生說
Excuse me
不好意思
sir, miss
先生、小姐
you got a graceful infection
你得了優美的感染
The doctor will prescribe medicine for you
醫生就給你開藥嘛
prescribe antibiotics
就開抗生素
only antibiotics
只有抗生素
What other treatment? No
其他有什麼治療?沒有
You just said you could have an important medical treatment?
你剛剛說可不可以吃個重要的醫治
he said no
他說不要吧
You just need to eat once
你只要去吃個需要吃一次就好了
Very cheap
很便宜
need really cheap now
現在需要真的很便宜
because I did it myself twice
因為我自己去做過兩次的
Treatment of Weiyan striae infection
衛炎紋路宣感染的治療
my friend also found
我朋友還發現
They actually put a lot of different antibiotics
他們其實是放了很多不同的抗生素
to do different treatments
去做不同的治療
now this is in
那現在這是在
A very similar one was published in 2011
2011年所發表的一個很類似的一個
Some of the currently used medical
現在目前醫學上屬用的一些
The three-in-one model of antibiotic treatment
抗生素的治療三合一的模式
But I'm breaking out with you that one of the antibiotics
但是我跟你們爆發其中有一個抗生素
This antibiotic is interesting
這抗生素挺有趣的
belly is nauseous bad fire
腹中就是噁心消防不良
stomach ache
腹痛
Bump
凹凸
have vomiting and diarrhea
有吐跟腹瀉
It then affects some liver functions
然後它會影響一些肝功能
or disabled patients
或是身功能不全的病犯
Causes excessive moisture growth of non-susceptible molds
造成非敏感性的黴菌的過濕生長
Then because of the superior blind spiral sense
然後因為優盲螺旋感
Because drug resistance develops in a small number of patients
因為在少部分的病患裡面會產生抗藥性
still develop resistance
還是會產生抗藥性
Everyone remember to go back first
大家且記先回去
If you think of what you are studying in Xinjiang today
如果大家想起今天在研疆什麼
must remember drug resistance
一定要想起抗藥性
bacterial resistance
細菌抗藥性
it's a very important noun
這是一個很重要的名詞
Another one is to say
另外一個就是說
a lot of these drugs
很多的這些藥物
If it is taken with other actually anti-drugs
如果和其他的居然的抗藥物一起吃的時候
Troublesome things that can cause some systemic metabolism
會引起一些系統代謝的很麻煩的事情
So it is in patients allergic to these anti-drugs
所以它對這些抗藥過敏的患者
it is unusable
它是不能使用的
But I remember the doctor didn't seem to ask me so much
但是我記得醫生好像也沒有問我這這麼多
He just prescribed the medicine
他就直接開藥物吃了
So we pass
所以我們透過
We will report to you first
我們接下來先跟大家報告
The antidote for vomiting and diarrhea just now
剛才吐跟腹瀉的抗藥物
We use electronic small cloud mirror
我們用電子小雲鏡
Just now there is a video to report to all of you
剛剛有一個影片跟你們大家報告
That is to say it will really
就是說它真的會把
Impressed by our Luo Sheng bacteria
為我們羅生感菌的打動
Slowly it will bubble after touching
打動以後慢慢的它會起泡
The contents will flow out
內容物就會流出去了
so you can see it's targeting
所以你可以看到它是針對
resembling a micro throw shape
類似一個微拋的形狀
To do the mechanism of impressing
來做打動的機制
this is a cartoon
這是一個卡通圖
TP4 it produces a pattern
TP4它產生的一個模式
It is similar to a carpet pattern
它是類似一個地毯的模式
covered in bacteria
鋪在細菌的
needs to be used on the cell membrane
需要被用細胞膜上面
then it goes inside
然後它進去裡面
resembling a microprojectile
類似一個微拋體
go in and impress it later
進去把它打動以後
let the contents flow out
讓裡面的東西流出來
And cause the death of Youneng Helix
而造成優能螺旋感變的死亡
At the same time, on the antigenic state of the grouper
同時在石斑魚的抗原態上面
We also did a similar experiment
我們也做類似的一個實驗
You can see that in this
你可以看到在這個
Electronic villain inspection map
電子小人驗圖
You can see it's all broken too
可以看到它也都破掉了
these bacteria are interesting
這些細菌挺有趣的
processed by these antigenic states
經過這些抗原態的處理
Bacteria completely disintegrated
細菌完全都瓦解掉了
Do you think of an interesting story
大家有沒有想到一個有趣的故事
These bacteria disintegrate
這些細菌瓦解掉
what will it become
會變成一個什麼東西呢
If you have learned
大家如果有學過
If you have a little impression
大家如果有一點小印象
that is you will
就是你們會
Do Chinese medicine practitioners say what to eat to make up for you?
中醫藥商們有說吃什麼補什麼嘛
right
對不對
you know these broken things
那你們知道這些破掉的東西
actually a good
其實是一個很好的
That is to say, it can cause the body's immune response to become an antibody
也就是說可以引起身體的免疫反應變成一個抗體
But antibodies can be synthesized in the future
但是抗體將來可以去綜合
Re-cleaning a new antigen
再清洗新來的一個抗原
So in the process of making a vaccine in the antigenic state
所以在抗原態做疫苗的過程裡面
Emerging in the process of making a vaccine
新興的一個疫苗製作的過程裡面
We use this model
我們就是利用這樣的模式
Go do some research on deep water life
去在水深生活上面做一些研究
And got a pretty good research result
而且得到一個還不錯的研究結果
Then you can see that EPI is in
那大家可以看到就是EPI在
Its mode is not the same as the mode since TP4 Wuguo just now
它的模式就跟剛剛TP4烏鍋以來的模式不太一樣
You can see that it's a
你可以看到就是說它這是一個
A bubble is a shape of a saddle created like this
一個泡泡就是馬鞍的一個形狀產生這樣
Then it popped like a balloon
然後爆破了就像氣球就爆掉了
Then break the cell coin or cell bone of this bacteria
然後把這個細菌的細胞幣或細胞骨弄破
then it broke
然後它就破了
Of course everyone just saw the so-called
當然大家剛剛看到都是所謂的
Experiments in the chamber
室管裡面的實驗
It's what we call an intraventricular experiment.
就是我們所謂的室管內的實驗
Invisal's experiment
invisal的實驗
Everyone will ask me
大家一定會問我說
Mr. Chen, you are really good at bragging
陳老師你真的會蠻會吹牛的
So what's going on inside the animal body?
那到底在動物體裡面到底怎麼樣
So let's try feeding the mice
所以我們就來餵老鼠試試看
because everyone likes me mouse
因為大家都喜歡我老鼠
Why
為什麼
Rats are all rats from heaven
老鼠從天家裡面都老鼠
So when you grow up, you have to do mouse experiments
所以長大也要做老鼠實驗
let's see then
那我們來看一下
We just started buying a bunch of rats that came in
我們剛開始買了一堆老鼠進來的
Of course these rats are not what everyone imagines outside
這些老鼠當然不是大家想像在外面
caught those mice
抓的那些老鼠
I remember when we were kids we were near the sugar cane fields
我記得小時候我們靠近甘蔗園
Sugarcane field full of voles
甘蔗園有很多田鼠
When you grab it, it's narrow enough to make soup with vegetables
抓起來就窄了就來做加菜的湯
But these mice are not this kind of mice
但是這些老鼠不是這種老鼠
It's an SPF mouse, a very expensive one.
這是SPF老鼠 一隻很貴的
This one of its white mice is white and fat
這一隻它的白色的老鼠長得白白又胖胖
Challenges that allow you to do different bacteria
可以讓你做不同的細菌的挑戰
then let you know say
然後讓你可以知道說
Did this experimental rat succeed?
這個實驗大鼠有成沒成
Of course animal rights groups may seriously protest that
當然了動保團體可能會嚴肅的抗議說
This white mouse can actually be a stupid mouse
這隻白色的老鼠其實是可以做蠢蠢鼠
But these white mice
但是然而這些白色老鼠
On the development of our biomedicine
在我們生物醫學的發展上面
They really are our heroes
它們真的是我們的英雄
unsung post-pregnancy animal heroes
無名的孕後動物英雄
What are we doing with these unsung animal heroes now
我們現在把這些無名的動物英雄做了什麼呢
Just let it acclimate to the environment for a while
就是讓它適應環境養一段時間
Then do two infections
然後做兩次感染
Just let it have in the stomach
就是讓它胃裡面有
Because of the growth of pylorospira infection
因為幽紋螺旋感染的生長
After growing we can put the mouse
生長以後我們可以把老鼠
After a week of growth
經過一個禮拜的生長
In time, we slaughtered the mice in the mouse part
在時間裡面我們就把老鼠部分的老鼠宰了
then feed it inside
然後把它餵裡面
Take a look to see if there is any generation of Yumen Luoxuan in it
看一看它裡面有沒有餵優門羅宣的產生
because if not
因為如果沒有的話
We mean we can't drug it
我們就代表說我們不能夠讓它灌藥物進去
Then we took what you all saw just now
後來我們就把剛剛你們大家看到
Shipan Fish Soup is the soup above the turtle
石磐魚羹是羹烏龜上面
The Anti-Yantai We Got
我們所得到的那個抗燕太
like you eat cold syrup
就類似你們吃感冒糖漿
Didi
滴滴
it didn't drip
它沒有滴滴
I don't know what rats taste like
我不知道老鼠吃起來的味道
Then I think it's Didi
然後我覺得是滴滴
Didi poured it into the rat's feed
滴滴就把它灌進去老鼠的餵裡面
let it eat
讓它吃了
So the rats ate for 14 days
所以老鼠吃了14天
We'll kill the rats again in two weeks
兩個禮拜以後我們再把老鼠給宰了
then watch it feed inside
然後看它餵裡面
Is there any production of Youmen Luoxuan?
有沒有餵優門羅宣的產生
We did a total of three different experiments
我們總共做了三種不同的實驗
An anti-yantai called rockfish
一個叫做石磐魚的抗燕太
An anti-yantai called turtle fish
一個叫做烏龜魚的抗燕太
One is currently used clinically
一個是現在臨床上所使用的
Three-in-one Anti-Agarin
三合一的抗燕素
But we didn't make one here
但我們這邊沒有做一個
Experiments with self-acids
自酸劑的實驗
because we thought of saying
因為我們想到說
Will there be no need to use self-acid in the future?
將來會不會不需要用自酸劑
you can pour the medicine in
就可以把藥物灌進去
So the experiment we poured in
所以我們灌進去的實驗
You can see this red mark error
可以看到這紅色的標誤
on the turtle fish
就是烏龜魚上
Anti-smoke titanium obtained above
上面所得到的抗菸鈦
You can see after we kill the rats
你可以看到我們殺老鼠以後
Where are these mice?
這幾隻老鼠呢
6 mice we got
6隻老鼠我們得到的
It turns out there's really nothing in it
結果它裡面真的沒有所謂的
Production of gastric pyloric helix infection
胃幽門螺旋感染的產生
We get really low levels of fine smoke from the stomach
我們從胃裡面得到細菸量真的很低
But without any medication
但是如果沒有做任何藥物處理的
its fine smoke is really high
它的細菸真的很高
You can see this 6
大家可以看到這個6
Digital Moon High Represents
數字月高代表
Rats with higher levels of fine smoke
老鼠體內的細菸量越高
Digital month low represents
數字月低代表
The amount of fine smoke in the mouse body is less
老鼠體內的細菸量越少
But you can see the three-in-one drug
但是你可以看到三合一的那個藥物呢
You can see its gastric pyloric helix infection
你可以看到它的胃幽門螺旋感染
still very high
還是非常高
Probably between 4, 4 and 5
大概到4、4到5之間
but we can see here
但是我們可以看到這邊
Probably below 1
大概降到1以下
The benefits of eating more black mushroom fish
那這些多吃烏菇魚的好處
Then this black mushroom fish is in the ecology we synthesized
那這個烏菇魚我們合成的生態裡面
you can see we are
你可以看到我們就是
This little bit of red is like thin smoke
這一點一點紅色的就是類似細菸
You can see that we use
你可以看到我們用
a particular coloring pattern
某種特殊的染色的模式
can see it these
可以看到它這些
what about these
這些呢
This time with a three-in-one
這次用三合一的
Mice treated with anti-smoke
抗菸所治療的老鼠
It still produces fine smoke
它還是有細菸的產生
But we use the anti-smoke of black mushroom fish to get in too much
但是我們用烏菇魚的抗菸太進去
Because there is basically no bacteria produced when it is ground inside.
因為裡面研磨出來基本上都沒有細菌產生
Those people didn't use any treatment first.
那這些人先沒有用任何處理的
It turns out that it has a lot of bacteria producing
它結果它都有很多的細菌產生
You see that click-throughs represent bacteria
你們看到那個點閱多代表細菌
Those are bacteria
那都是一顆一顆細菌
What about these groupers
那這些石斑魚上面所
An antigen embryo obtained by clicking on a grouper
點在石斑魚上面所得到的一個抗原胎
You can also see the same result
你們也可以看到同樣的結果
This red is also marked
這紅色也是標
That is to say, the antigen embryo obtained from the grouper
就是說這個石斑魚上面得到的抗原胎
It is also possible to put rats in the stomach
它也是可以把胃裡面老鼠
The stomach feeling is very low
胃裡面的優門感就壓得非常量低
So this gives us a new hope
所以這給我們一個新的希望
I just had a Psychedelic
就是我剛剛有一張幻能片
Tell everyone about the emerging drugs in the future of mankind
告訴大家說人類未來的新興的藥物
Could it be obtained from water porridge?
會不會是從水生粥裡面得到的
That's the very special PCR principle we use
那這是我們用很特殊的那個PCR原理
There is also the Western target point analysis method of the protein pattern
還有蛋白質的模式的那個西方式目點分析法
Verify that there is still a mouse in the body
驗證是個還有老鼠體內
yes and those bacteria
是個還有那些細菌
Then we can all find out that
那我們都可以發現到說
If there is no treatment, there are antigens to eat
如果沒有治療有吃的抗原胎
Basically you can see that there are no class fragments here
基本上你可以看到這邊都沒有類成的片段
without any white fragments
沒有任何白色的片段
It means that there is no such bacteria produced
就代表都沒有那細菌的產生
Ok so we get an interesting result
好 所以我們得到一個有趣的結果
that is
就是說
This mouse is very cute. The mouse ate Youmenyou's sour bacteria
這個老鼠很可愛的老鼠吃了優門優的酸感菌
It really has Acidophilus bacteria in it
它裡面真的有餵優門優酸感菌
very similar to human infection
很類似人類傳染
Humans are also passed through food, kissing, and infection
人類也是經過食物、接吻、傳染過來的
We also let it eat our disease-resistant fetus later
我們也讓它吃了我們的抗病胎以後
Through these experiments, we all found that it really chewed off
透過這些實驗我們都發現它真的都咀嚼掉了
This is our conclusion that
這是我們的結論就是說
I have not mentioned some regulatory factors of immunity here
免疫的一些調控因子我沒有在這邊講
because that is cumbersome
因為那個很繁瑣
So I can only talk about the results of animal experiments
所以我只有講動物實驗的結果
Then what is my second little experiment to report to you?
那我第二個小實驗要跟大家報告的是什麼
Everyone will be tired, right?
大家都會累慘對不對
there may be some people who are not tired
可能有一些人不會累慘
But when I was in college I was tired and miserable
但是我從大學的時候我有累過慘
Tired and painful Tired and miserable
累完慘又很痛苦累慘
just fell off a motorcycle
就是騎摩托車摔倒
You can see that car slowly coming
你就看到那個車子緩緩的開過來
People slowly rubbed against the ground
人就緩緩地在地上摩擦摩過去
Then you wonder why my parking space can't be blocked
然後你就覺得奇怪我的車位怎麼擋不住
Why does it keep coming to the opposite parking space?
它對面車位怎麼一直過來
And when you get up you see a little gash on your leg
然後起來的時候你就看到你的腿上有一個小傷口
You touch that gun and it won't hurt
你摸下去那一槍它不會痛
Really I think the wheel is really very very
真是我覺得輪真的是非常非常
You won't find out until you wake up and find it broken
等你起來發現破的時候才會發現
Why is your leg hurting and bleeding
你怎麼腿在痛在流血
Alright, everyone, did you think you would stay
好啦 大家有沒有想到你們留
Have you looked closely at your wounds?
你們有沒有仔細看你們的傷口
The wound will flow out in the process of bathing in the river
傷口在浴河的過程會流出
yellow sticky sticky
黃黃的黏稠黏稠
Sometimes it smells so bad
有時候生出來臭臭的很好聞
right
對不對
Have you ever touched and smelled it yourself?
你們有沒有自己摸起來聞過
you know what that is
你們知道那是什麼
that very very very interesting person
那非常非常非常有趣的人
I may really have nothing to do since I was in college.
我從年從年大學可能真的沒事可幹
internal trouble
內患慘 用的傷口結架
it's itchy
就很癢
Itches and you want to pull out the wound
癢你就會想要把傷口給拔起來
In the process of pulling it up, it will start to bathe in the wound
拔起來的過程它就會在那傷口開始浴河
I just look at my wounds every day
我就每天都看我的傷口
start to bathe in the river
開始浴河
Then there is a little white yellow juice flowing out
然後就有一點白白的黃黃的濃汁流出來
And then it smells really good
然後聞起來臭臭的蠻好聞的
I later found out that it was bacteria
後來我才知道那個是細菌
immune cells in your body
你的身體面的免疫細胞
Giant Cell Moderate HP
巨式細胞 適中彈血
The structure under the suspicion of contact with bacteria
跟細菌打仗所殘疑下的結構
stinks is some of it
臭臭的是它的一些
that product
那個產物
Alright, let's talk to you now
好啦 我們現在跟大家講
Everyone must remember
大家一定還記得
These two things happened in 2014 and 2015
2014年跟2015年所發生的這兩件事情
How many people died, how many people were injured
死了多少人 受傷了多少人
We won't be a rich prize here
我們在這邊就不成富獎了
but it's a hassle
但是這是一個很麻煩的事情
so traumatized
所以創傷
Everyone should see
大家小偶看應該
Mr. Chen, you always ride a motorcycle
陳老師 按你從來騎摩托車
a wound like a big one
創傷那麼一大塊的傷口
You're still here to tell us all
你還是活在這邊跟我們大家講
Tell us about science salary
跟我們大家講科學薪資
Then why do these people just hang up?
那為什麼這些人就是掛掉呢
wait a minute and you'll see
等一下你們就知道
little trauma
小小的小創傷
mainly cause them
主要導致他們
they get bacterial infections
他們得到細菌感染
At the same time, I also got what I just reported to you
同時也得到剛剛我跟大家報告的
sepsis after bacterial infection
細菌感染以後的敗血症
So we experimentally
所以我們在實驗上
we just want us to hurt
我們就想要我們創傷
Because I just reported to you
因為我剛跟大家報告
Although I studied marine biology in college
我大學雖然是念海洋學習生物組
But when I was in college, I used to take pictures of horse races
但是我大學時常就跑馬照
Then the photos of the horse race often leave the disabled
然後跑馬照就時常離殘
Trauma
離殘就有創傷
so i just keep watching my legs
所以我就一直觀察我的腿
I can think about it later
後來我可以再想
One day in the middle of the lab I found out that the mouse is a great friend again
在實驗室中間有一天我發現到老鼠又是一個很好的朋友
another unsung hero
又是無名英雄
Well the unsung hero we bought these mice again
那這無名英雄我們再次買了這些老鼠
Then we created a 1 cm by 1 cm wound on him
然後我們在他身上製造一個1公分成1公分的創傷
So what do we deal with this trauma? Deal with the antibacterial state
那這創傷我們就處理什麼?處理抗菌態
This is what we use Staphylococcus aureus
這是我們用金黃色葡萄球菌
Oxygen Resistant
就是抗耐假氧吸淋
Staphylococcus aureus
金黃色葡萄球菌
This bacterial infection is currently in the hospital
這個細菌感染現在目前在醫院裡面
Still a bacterial infection with a really bad headache
還是一個頭非常痛的細菌感染
is a lot of time
就是大量的時候
Then let's take this mouse
那我們就把這個老鼠
Doesn't it have iron plates with a size of 1 cm and 1 cm square on its back?
它的背上不是有用1公分跟1公分建方的鐵板燙下去
The mouse will come out with a slight trauma
老鼠就會有稍微的一個小創傷出來
Then we take the amount of bacteria to the 6th power of 10
那我們就把10的6次方的細菌的量
10 to the power of 6 the amount of bacteria each mouse drops on it
10的6次方細菌的量每一隻老鼠滴在它上面
This bacteria will grow on the back of its mouse
這個細菌就會長在它的老鼠背部
then becomes an infected open wound
然後變成一個感染性的開放性的傷口
As you can see this has been the result of what I think we did for 14 days
大家可以看到這已經我覺得我們做了14天的結果
Report to everyone that this is the plugging group
跟大家報一下這是扛塞組
It's the control group, it's the mouse
就是控塞組就是這個老鼠
Did not put any bacteria, and did not put any treatment
沒有放任何的細菌,也沒有放任何的處理
it will add up by itself, it will start
它自己就會結加,就會開始
Because it uses its own body immunity to do wound healing
因為它透過它自己身體免疫力來做傷口癒合
But there is MRSA, have you seen the yellow over here
但是有MRSA,你有沒有看到這邊黃黃的
we're the ones who stink and have fun
我們才臭臭的,很有趣
This is the result of bacterial infection
這就是細菌感染以後的結果
It's about ninety-six hours after the fourth day
它大概第四天九十六小時以後
The mouse is dead
這個老鼠就死掉了
But if because it's MRSA bacteria
但是如果因為這是MRSA的細菌
It allows the so-called venomission
它可以讓所謂的venomission
All things, enzymes, antibiotics for treatment
萬物,酶素,抗生素做治療
because it's going to kill this, i just said
因為它會殺這個,我剛剛講過
There are some antibiotics that kill certain bacteria
有一些抗生素可以殺某些細菌
Some bacteria can be killed by certain antibiotics
有些細菌可以讓某些抗生素殺掉
You can see that the skin is still very well restored
你可以看看它皮膚還是復原得非常好
very beautiful
非常漂亮
But if this MRSA bacteria
但是如果這個MRSA的細菌
Because the M is the antibiotic
因為這個M就是這個抗生素
This MRSA bacteria, because resistant to this antibiotic
這MRSA的細菌,因為抗這種抗生素
So even if you go on this antibiotic
所以即使你用了這種抗生素下去
The mouse is over
這老鼠還是過了
Simple and easy to report to everyone
簡單的很容易的跟大家報告
Maybe watch me here for a second
大概這邊看我講一秒鐘
This mouse is dead
這個老鼠就掛了
but think about it
但是大家想一想
on top of humans
在人類上面
If you experience a bacterial infection with this antibiotic
如果你遇到這種抗生素的細菌感染的時候
It will hang up in 96 hours soon
很快96小時就掛了
so you think about it
所以你想想
We are looking for a new
我們是要找一個新興的
Drugs that can replace antibiotics
可以取代抗生素的藥物
ok let's see next
好啦 我們接下來看
EPI is what I just told you
EPI就是我剛剛跟你們講
Antibacterial status obtained by pointing on the rice
點在食飯上面所得到抗菌態
The probability of 33 is that I just reported to you
機率33就是我剛剛跟大家報告
That one nose got antibacterial status
那一隻鼻子上面得到抗菌態
Add collagen this time
這次加膠原蛋白
Because everyone is emphasizing beauty now
因為大家現在強調美容
When many wounds heal
有很多的傷口復原的時候
no scars
不能有疤
or if you are on medication
或是你在藥物處理的過程
I also want collagen
也希望有膠原蛋白
Can promote wound healing
能夠促使傷口癒合
we can see that is to say
我們可以看到就是說
Meals also come to an antibacterial state
食飯也來到抗菌態
how well its wounds heal
它傷口癒合的情況
very beautiful by the tenth day
到第十十天非常漂亮
All the hair has grown back
整個毛都重新長起來了
if you add collagen
如果你加了膠原蛋白
Its fur grows more beautifully and faster
它的毛長得更漂亮更快
So we believe in collagen
所以我們相信在膠原蛋白
We see him mixed in with the anti-morbid process
我們看他混合在抗病態的過程裡面
Just now as a raw drug
剛才當一個原藥物的
Quality of Raw Drugs
原料藥品的質
Then he went forward and came out
然後他前行是已經出來了
so he can see him
所以他可以看得到他
When the third day started here
這邊剛開始第三天的時候
and a little yellow
還有一點黃黃的
But in the end he did really well
但是到最後他都表現得非常好
Let's look at the angiogenesis treated by these drugs
我們再看這些藥物處理的血管新生
Why do you want to explode angiogenesis with everyone?
為什麼要跟大家爆發血管新生生生
you may not know
你們可能有所不知
there are some models
有一些模特兒
or some ambiguous people
或是有一些曖昧的人士
It's not just a trio of jades
這不是只有三口玉合
Some people because he wants to wear
有些人他因為要穿
wear some swimwear
穿一些泳裝
or some people
或是有一些人
he has three mouths in the face
他在臉上有三口
He hoped that his three jades would be on Mino Medicine
他希望他的三口玉合在美濃醫學上面
I hope he will have a lot of angiogenesis
希望他三口玉合的血管新生很多
Because this will cause a scar to come out
因為這樣都會流出一個疤出來
so you can see
所以你可以看到
We are in the whole process of angiogenesis
我們在整個血管新生過程裡面
If you have added anti-morbid process
如果你有加抗病態的過程
You can all see it like this anti-morbid
你都可以看到像這個抗病態
or this flounder's disease-resistant
或是這個比目魚的抗病態
You can see that his angiogenesis is beautiful
你都可以看到他血管新生非常漂亮
If comparing a control group
如果比對一個控制組
Or for groups with ice or microphones
或是加冰或麥克風的組別來講
he finally
他終於
Those new students are very beautiful
那些學款的新生生都非常漂亮
then it has another
那它是有另外一個
The other is called can promote
另外一個叫做可以促進
Stimulus for production technology
生產技術的刺激產生
We are still doing related research
目前我們還在做相關的研究
Then we can report to you
那我們可以跟大家報告一下
This is the main part of MRSA
這是MRSA的主別
I just told you
我剛剛有跟大家講
Is the ancestor dead?
老祖死了嘛
But scientific research cannot say that he is dead
但是科學研究上不能說他死了
Scientific research must ask why
科學研究上面一定要問為什麼
Has the number of bacteria in the ancestors been suppressed?
老祖裡面的細菌數量有沒有被壓下來
If it's not pressed down you can see it's funny
如果沒有壓下來你可以看到很有趣
Sometimes we go home when the drug is actually administered
實際上給藥的時候有時候我們回家
medicine prescribed by your doctor
醫生開給你的藥
Everyone take one medicine and you don't take it if you feel better
大家吃一隻藥你覺得好一點就不吃了
Doctors sometimes prescribe a three- or seven-day regimen
醫生有時候開三天或七天的藥
there is a reason for it
是有它的原理的
For example, when your bacterial count is suppressed
譬如說你的細菌量壓下來的時候
you feel like a doctor
你自己就覺得自己是醫生
No more antibiotics or medicine
就不吃抗生素也不吃藥了
Then your bacteria count went up again
那你的細菌量又上去了
Then what will happen after this goes up?
那這上去以後會造成什麼
secondary infection
二次感染
then it was more troublesome
那時候這是更麻煩的時候
So you can see that is
所以你可以看到就是說
We use Jialin Xilin as just mentioned
我們用賈林西林就是剛剛所講
More troublesome, he has many side effects
比較麻煩他很多的副作用
but now
但是呢在現在
If this anti-pseudobacteria
如果這個抗假離細菌的細菌
in mice
在老鼠體內
It's about the fourth day it's all dead
它大概在第四天它就整個都死掉
So the bacteria here just can't see any bacteria
所以這邊細菌就是看不到任何細菌
We can't see the fungus that we drew blood from the mice
我們把老鼠的血抽出來的圖菌看不到
But if you use the TP3 from the turtle and hedgehog
但如果你用烏龜蝟上面來的TP3
Or the EBI from the grouper hedgehog
或是石斑蝟上面來的EBI
You can see it on day 17
你可以看到第17天的時候
Its bacterial count is almost zero
它細菌量幾乎都是變零
It means that it no longer has this kind of bacteria in its body
代表它體內已經沒有這種細菌了
These bacteria were killed by our anti-pregnancy
這細菌都被我們用抗孕胎給殺掉了
So anti-pregnancy may be a
所以抗孕胎可能是一種
the future may be a
將來可能是一種
Medicines for burns and skin infections
燒燙傷皮膚感染的藥物
Everyone will definitely say that Mr. Chen knew that he was a mouse
大家一定會說陳老師他明知有做老鼠
How do I know the rats are fun for everyone
我怎麼知道老鼠大家做都很愉快
Every time you make a mouse, you will have a lot of
大家每次做老鼠都會有一大堆的
Experimental results that seem to have potential
好像有潛力的實驗結果
So we're going to be pigs
所以我們就去做豬了
Then why else?
那另外為什麼呢
Because of the pig I think I have a real bond with it
因為豬我覺得我跟它真的很有感情
If this pig succeeds
這個豬如果做成功
It will also be similar to medium and large animals.
也會類似中大型動物成功了
Then what's the king next?
那接下來再接下來是王什麼
We hope to be able to enter the so-called clinical testing
我們就希望能夠進入到所謂的臨床的測試
For example, using monkeys or using pre-clinical tests to find some CRL companies
譬如說用猴子或是用前臨床測試找了一些CRL公司
It is the clinical testing company that helps us do these tests
就是臨床測試的公司幫我們做這些測試
You can see that it is the same in the experimental process of strains
你看看它在株的實驗過程裡面也是一樣
We use the anti-morbidity from the grouper
我們用石斑魚上面來的抗病態
We use 1000 times or 100 times or 10 times the number of MIC
我們用1000倍的或是100倍或10倍的MIC的數量
In addition, we have a 14-party MSA that is 10 higher on the plant this time.
加上我們這次株上面有更高10的14方MSA的峻下去塗
you can see it to the end
你可以看到它到最後
In fact, the wound area is doing very well.
其實它傷口的區域都表現得非常好
10 of 14 party MSA, you can see its bacteria and its wound sealing speed is not so fast
10的14方MSA你看它的細菌、它的傷口封口的速度就沒有那麼快
In all this 25th day
在這所有的第25天裡面
Look at the different bacterial infections and different treatment processes this time
你看這次不同的細菌感染跟不同的處理過程
For example, we use 10 times the number of MIC
譬如說我們用10倍MIC的數量
MIC is the minimum concentration of bacteria that can kill bacteria
MIC就殺菌的最小一支細菌濃度
You can see the amount of EPI we use 10 times the MIC
你可以看到我們用10倍MIC的EPI的量
You can see it grow over time
可以看到它隨著時間的生長
it precloses the wound very well
它傷口預合得非常好
If you use 100 times the amount of MIC
如果你用100倍MIC的數量
It wound up running away for the last 25 days
它到最後25天傷口跑掉
will run faster
會跑得更快
Kamdor is like a mouse
卡姆多就是像老鼠一樣
nothing goes out
什麼都沒有出去
just heat it up
只是把它燙上而已
If we use 1000 times the MIC
如果我們用1000倍的MIC
this EPI
這個EPI
then you can see
然後你可以看到
it is also
它也是
Also the wound is also very good
也是傷口也是非常好
but we later
但是我們以後
If it is really eaten at the waist
如果真的在腰食用上
We don't need to use 1000 times
我們就不用用到1000倍
that is expensive
那個很花錢
so we can grab a
所以我們就可以抓一個
good connections
很好的門路
market we are above pigs
市場我們在豬上面
good results on mice
老鼠上面得到好的結果
We also get good results on pigs
我們在豬上面也得到很好的結果
make us more confident
讓我們更有信心
Can advance to clinical
可以往臨床推進
So we can all report
所以我們大家可以跟大家報告一下
Anti-Tiantai MAB can be used as
抗天太MAB可以當作
I also come to fight the substitute
我也來抗爭的替代物
Then Anti-Tiantai did not cause immune stimulation
然後抗天太並沒有引起免疫刺激
At least we have partial results
至少我們有部分的結果
have told us
已經告訴我們
It does not cause bothersome immune stimulation
它並沒有引起很麻煩的免疫刺激
Another one is
另外一個就是
We hope that the research results can be sold into clinical trials.
研究成果我們希望能夠往臨床測試的賣進
Everyone after Lei gave birth
大家雷產以後
A foreshadowing of what I just said
我剛剛有講的一個伏筆
After Lei gave birth, I said
雷產以後我說
You won't be in pain during Ray's process
在雷的過程中你不會痛的
But when it thunders you will hurt
但雷起來以後你會痛
Everyone will feel pain
大家都會有疼痛的感覺
in the burn process
在燒燙傷過程
or when you pick your wounds
或是你有摳傷口的時候
Everyone will be in pain, it is impossible that no one will not be in pain, right?
大家都會痛,不可能沒有人不會痛的吧
Well, in the process of going through the pain, you will think of one thing
好,以過痛的過程裡面,你就會想到一件事
Is there any possibility of anti-morbidity in treating the wound healing process
抗病態有沒有可能在治療傷口癒合的過程
Make wounds painless, or humans painless, or animals painless
讓傷口不會痛,或是讓人不會痛,或是讓動物不會痛
So I went to find a very good friend named Teacher Wen Zhirong
所以我就去找了一個很好的朋友叫溫志榮老師
He is a teacher at Zhongshan University
他是中山大學老師
We use an anti-pathological agent called PCDI1
我們使用一個抗病態叫PCDI1
In 2015 we were able to know that
我們在2015年我們能夠知道說
We know from the ancestors that it is anti-morbid
在老祖上面我們知道說這個抗病態
It actually has the effect of suppressing pain
它竟然會有抑制疼痛的效果
it's really fun
這真的是挺有趣的
So we hope to develop into a drug in the future
所以我們希望將來能夠發展成一個藥品
Applying this can not only make the wound heal well
這個塗上去不僅可以使傷口癒合的很好
It can kill bacteria and make the pain less painful
可以殺菌,也可以讓疼痛不會那麼痛
you may not know
你們可能不知道
those in the process of burn injury
那些在燒傷傷的過程裡面
For example, the gas explosion in Kaohsiung just mentioned
譬如說剛剛有講的高雄的氣爆
or a burn at an amusement park
或是在遊樂園的燒傷傷
General burns such as general chairs
一般的燒傷傷譬如說一般椅子
In fact, there are already flower feet at home.
其實在家裡面就已經有花腳
If the whole body has 2, 30% barbecue
如果全身有2、30%的燒烤
that was excruciatingly painful
那個是痛到不得了的
So our Western family is on drug development
所以我們西洋家人在藥物開發上面
In addition to our drug can have many different functions
除了我們這個藥物就可以有很多不同的功能
I'm going to talk about my last chop
接下來我要講我最後一個chop
The last study result
最後一個研究結果
I told you about cancer when I first started
癌症我剛開始的時候有跟大家報告
3 million is not a small number
300萬不是一個小數目
Ordinary people in the process of cancer treatment
一般人在做癌症治療的流程裡面
For example, the process of doing PL-1
譬如說做PL-1的流程
Now the latest process is 3 million
現在最新的流程要300萬
But is there any possibility that we can reduce the process of it
但是有沒有可能我們可以降低它的過程
lower its price
降低它的價格
Because we use a simple anti-pregnancy state for treatment
因為我們很簡單的抗孕態來做治療
This is an anti-pregnancy state we got
這是我們所得到的一個抗孕態
We do some antibacterial ecology
我們做一些抗菌的生態
3491 articles were published from 1990 to 2015
從1990到2015年共發表了3491篇的文章
currently existing
現在現有的
Our anti-pregnancy state, let us first introduce
我們抗孕態我們先介紹
This generation is an anti-pregnancy state above the flounder
這個世代是比目魚上面一個抗孕態
Our name is Potassium
我們叫Potassium
The anti-pregnancy description is probably listed here
這個抗孕態敘略大概列在這邊
It is also an anti-pregnancy state that can impress
它也是一個可以打動的一個抗孕態
that this generation
那這世代
Humans have a thing called fibrous meat flow
人類上面有一個叫做纖維肉流
So-called fibromyalgia can also be seen on dogs or cats
在狗或貓上面也會有所謂的纖維肉流
All of you should, if you have ever had pets,
你們大家應該如果有養過寵物的
The older your dog is, the more it will give birth
你們狗越老,牠會生牠會長一顆一顆
messy stuff
亂七八糟的東西
There are a lot of fiber meat flow
有很多都是纖維肉流
Of course, it can be removed directly by surgery.
當然可以用手術直接切掉
This can be surgically removed
這樣都可以用手術切掉
This can also be surgically removed
這也可以用手術切掉
But some surgical cuts can really be done with a knife
但是有些手術切掉的過程是真的能夠動刀
This incident caused many surgeons to raise a question mark
這件事情讓很多外科醫生提出一個問號
I give an example
我舉一個例子
Some people here will get oral cancer
這邊有些人會得口腔癌
Some people will swell up a big pile on this side, a big ball
有些人會在這邊腫了一大堆,一大球
The surgeon moved the knife when there was a big ball
一大球的時候外科醫生動刀
it will be tim gu ass skin flesh to fill this side
牠會被添穀屁股的皮膚肉來補這邊的
But sometimes when the dirty mouth is too big
但是有時候臟口太大的時候
It dare not move a knife
牠也不敢動刀
So when we first started doing anti-cancer experiments
所以在我們剛開始做抗癌實驗的時候
We discuss the results with the surgeon
我們跟外科醫生討論結果
They just want us to find a way to shrink the tumor
他們就希望我們能夠想辦法把腫瘤縮小
Then let them move the knife to do the experiment
然後讓牠們可以動刀來做實驗
so we now
所以我們現在
Later, we chose this anti-cancer
後來我們就先選了這個抗癌
We make fiber meat flow HT1080 is a fiber meat flow for human beings
我們做纖維肉流HT1080是人類的一個纖維肉流
Let's fight on the snail
我們就在螺鼠上面打
We can see it after playing
我們可以看到它打了以後
We're doing anti-facial injections
我們在做抗面態的注射
injection on the tumor
在腫瘤上面注射
It really has something to do with the control group
它真的有跟控制組來講
it really has some differences
它真的有一些差異
Difference in Tumor Size
腫瘤大小的差異
That's the Golden Collie
那這是黃金列犬
wait a minute i'll tell you
等一下我會跟你們講
The golden collie later we were on the mouse and it was still the same
黃金列犬後來我們在老鼠上面還是一樣
we have a lot of time
我們做時間就很有
we do
我們做
It's not just experiments that want to do rats
不是只有想要做老鼠的實驗
Experiments in my lab
在我實驗室裡面的實驗
We all hope that when we're done with the fish
我們都希望從魚身上做完以後
mouse that made a butterfly
做到蝴蝴類的老鼠
and then to medium and large animals
然後再往中大型動物
How about doing it on a dog or a pig
不如說狗或是豬身上做
In the future, if our laboratory hypocrisy fish
以後如果我們實驗室虛偽魚
We also hope to cooperate with others
我們也希望跟人家合作
Experiments that can be done on monkeys
能夠做到猴子身上去的實驗
That's an experiment on dogs
那這是狗的身上的實驗
We can see some microsteel flow in the dog
我們可以看到狗的一些微鋼流
you can see a different dog this time
你可以看到這次不同的狗
this is husky hal
這是哈士奇哈爾
Howl's dog
哈爾的狗
that's a mixed dog
那這是混合的狗
just normal
就是一般的
Then this time, let's look at this dog
然後這次敘失,我們先來看這一隻狗
On the seventeenth day of the tumor on the back side of the steel gate we punched in
在鋼門的背側腫瘤第十七天我們打進去
A large tumor can be seen
可以看到一顆腫瘤很大
Then today we are Theorem Yuntian
那今天我們就是定理雲天了
Then at the ten thousandth time
然後第十千的時候
We can see that the tumor is starting to fade a bit
我們可以看到它腫瘤開始有點消掉
During those nineteen days and twenty-six days
那十九天跟二十六天的時候
Its tumors have actually been affected by our drugs.
它的腫瘤其實都已經對我們的藥物進去以後
disintegrated its tumor
把它腫瘤給瓦解掉了
On the thirty-seventh day, thirty-three day, thirty-seventh day
到第三十七天、三十三天、三十七天的時候
We can see that the tumor is completely gone
我們可以看到腫瘤完全都不見了
In dogs at the ninety-third day after cessation of spanking
在狗身上在停止施打以後第九十三天的時候
The dog's tumors are completely gone
狗的腫瘤完全都沒有了
The dog is alive and well and happy
這隻狗活得很好、很愉快
Then we changed the PET bottle to let you tell Zhizhi
那我們換寶特瓶是讓你跟知道說
How big is this dog
這隻狗大概有多大隻
then we can know
那我們可以知道說
In dogs we have tumors
在狗的身上我們腫瘤
then we have to ask another question
那我們還要問另外一個問題
Is it only the anti-pregnancy effect on the Bilu fish that I just ate?
是不是只有剛剛吃的比露魚身上的那個抗孕胎有效益
So we start with what we do every day
所以我們就從我們日常做的
Real thing over the above to get another anti-pregnancy
實班物過於上面的得到另外一個抗孕胎
called TP4
叫做TP4
Then the anti-pregnancy on the turtle
那這個烏龜上面的抗孕胎
it probably has...
它大概有...
There are five types of antimicrobial cancer
有五種類型的抗菌癌
But when we were doing MIC
但是我們在做MIC的時候
we can know say
我們可以知道說
TP4 number fourth this anti-cancer is the best
TP4編號第四個這個抗菌癌是最好的
Its bactericidal ability is the best
它殺菌能力是最好
Usually it has the best bactericidal ability
通常它的殺菌能力最好
We think it's also good against cancer
我們覺得它抗癌的效果也會很好
so we can
所以我們可以
At the beginning, we chose trinity breast cancer
剛開始做我們是選擇三一性乳癌的
Trinity breast cancer is currently in the negative category of breast cancer
三一性乳癌是目前在負擬的乳癌裡面
The tightest in treatment
在治療上面最擠手的
because it is
因為它是
It has these three different
它有這三種不同的
Variations in different genes
不同的基因上面的一些變化
So it's troublesome on medication
所以它在藥物治療上面很麻煩
Some Drugs Actually Don't Work Against Trinity Breast Cancer
有些藥物其實對三一性乳癌是沒有用的
In terms of treatment
在治療上面來講
So we're going to fight on Lord Luo
所以我們就在羅主上面打
Lord Luo, we can see
羅主上面我們可以看到
This is a general KY dye cream
這是一般的KY染膏
we are on the lord
我們在羅主上面
Added ours with KY dye cream
用KY染膏加了我們的
Antibacterial tire of black spinach puree
烏菠泥的抗菌胎
you can see its tumor
你可以看到它的腫瘤
start getting small
都開始變得很小
especially you can see that is to say
尤其你可以看到就是說
Only with KY dyeing cream alone
只有單獨打KY染膏的
Now add tumor cells
現在加上腫瘤細胞
it's on top of whole milk
它在整支老乳上面
it varies greatly
它變異的非常大
but if we add we add
但如果我們加了我們加了
Antibacterial tires
部部的抗菌胎
Then you can see it whole
然後你可以看到它整個
actually shrunk
其實都縮小了
Including we can use some tissue immune infection
包括我們可以用一些組織免疫染症
It can be seen that the IC packages in its anti-tire have been changed.
可以看到它的抗胎裡面這些IC包都變掉了
are smaller
都比較縮小了
There is no only KI in it.
那沒有只有KI的它裡面都
The other parts are the so-called IC package
其他部分都是所謂的IC包
So we did it on the mouse
所以我們在老鼠上面做完
We also use fish for verification
我們也有用魚來做驗證
Because in Lin Hai's research, when we talk about
因為在林海研究中在我們講
The zebrafish is a very, very simple story
斑馬魚是一個非常非常簡單的故事
very easy little technique
非常容易的一個小技術
So our example on the fish
所以我們在魚上面的譬如說
The three slices of cells from which we
這三一片細胞我們從它的
Punch in from the vein of its heart
從它的這個心臟的靜脈這邊打進去
it can be right here
它就可以在這邊
has a colored cell
有一個帶有顏色的細胞
Go up and type in the red IC bag
紅色的IC包上去打進去
you can see that
你就可以看到說
After the chair passed
椅子過胞以後
Its IC package will grow over time
它的IC包會隨著時間的增長
to circulate throughout the body of the fish
而去循環到魚的全身
But if we add TV4 later
但如果我們加了TV4以後
You'll be able to see the IC package that says it's
你就可以看到說它的IC包
actually started getting smaller
其實開始越來越小
was spun off by Juju or even killed.
就被橘旋掉甚至被殺掉了
this is a short video
這是一個小影片
This is the video we shot
這是我們所拍的影片
you can see that is to say
你可以看得到就是說
what about this fish
這隻魚呢
when it is not treated with any medication
它沒有做任何藥物處理的時候
This red IC is wrapped in its body
這個紅色IC包在它身裡面
it grows over time
它隨著時間的增長
the fish finally exploded
魚最後就爆了
like just saw
就像剛看到的
IC package if not processed
IC包如果不處理
then it will explode
到時候它就爆了
because it's getting bigger
因為它越來越大
But what if our fish
但是如果我們這個魚呢
We carefully put three high-roller TP4s in it
我們每一細心裡面放三個豪客的TP4
Let's see how it turns out
我們來看一下它會變成什麼樣子
What about the IC bag?
這IC包呢
it will start shrinking
它會開始縮小
as time increases
隨著時間的增加以後
it starts to disappear
它開始變不見了
But this IC package passes through this fish
可是這個IC包經過這個魚
Soak in water containing anti-cigarette
在泡在含有抗菸泰的水裡面
Its IC package was killed by our anti-yantai
它IC包被我們的抗菸泰殺掉了
so what do we want to do in the future
所以我們將來想要做什麼呢
We want to talk to a doctor in the future
我們將來想要跟一個醫生
say these parents' breast cancer wounds
說這些父母的乳癌的傷口
You can see it learns in tacit understanding
你可以看到它學在默契的時候
ribs can be seen
都可以看到肋骨
We also hope to build a pet market
我們也希望能夠建立一個寵物的市場
Then let's go back to bacteria
那接下來我們回到細菌來講
bacteria you can see that is to say
細菌你可以看到就是說
resistant bacteria
這些抗藥性的細菌
now we can know
現在我們可以知道
There are many, many, including the United States, including China, are very, very troubled by bacterial infections
有很多很多包括美國,包括中國都非常非常的對細菌感染非常頭痛
Especially like mainland China, I think they have recently been on the weakest magazines in recent years
尤其像中國大陸我想這幾年他們最近有邊在次弱雜誌上面
They talked about the emergence of drug-resistant bacteria on pigs in many areas
他們有談到他們在很多地區的豬上面發現抗藥性的細菌產生
so it's a headache
所以這是一個很頭痛的問題
In March 2015 when Obama was President Obama
在2015年的3月歐巴馬那時候還是歐巴馬總統的時候
he has signed a bill
他有簽署一個法案
What is this bill for?
就是這個法案是幹嘛呢?
The plan of this bill is to invest a lot of money
這個法案的計畫就是說投入大量的資金
Seeking scientists from all over the world to cooperate with American scientists
尋求全世界的科學家跟美國科學家合作
Conduct an antimicrobial resistant bacteria to find a new type of drug
進行一個對抗藥性的細菌來找一個新型的藥物
to deal with new drug-resistant bacteria
來對新型抗藥性的細菌做一個處理
The bill is now signed
目前這個法案已經簽署完成了
So we're probably this is what I'm just starting out with
所以我們大概這是我剛剛在剛開始的時候
In March 2016, a magazine told us
在2016年的3月已經有一篇雜誌告訴我們
A report in an editorial magazine told us that
有編雜誌上面一個報告告訴我們說
Scientists in Spain find human-raised dog feces inside
西班牙的科學家發現人類飼養的狗糞便裡面
A bacterium of such a family as Eubacteriaceae
具有這樣的一個常感菌科的細菌
So what is the existence of this bacteria?
那這細菌的存在是什麼?
There will be a major threat to human health and benefits
對人類健康跟受益會有一大的威脅
Everyone, don't forget what I just told you
大家不要忘記剛剛我跟大家講
What happens to dog poop?
狗大便會怎樣?
Sometimes pets are in the process of excreting
有時候寵物在排泄的過程裡面
we all stay at home
我們都養在家裡面
Because I have a friend who has two small, new dogs at home
因為我有一個朋友家裡面養了兩隻小的、小新的狗
I see he's a dog if he poops
我看到他就是狗如果大小便的時候
Just take the toilet paper and insert it yourself
就自己拿衛生紙去插
I don't know if it was absorbed after insertion
插完以後有沒有吸收我不知道
But in the process of inserting
但是插的過程裡面
Think about it, if there's germs in it, it's on your hands
你想想如果這裡面有細菌就是在你的手上
When you don't want to play when you eat
當你吃東西的時候不想玩吃東西的時候
eat it in your stomach
就吃到你的肚子裡面
I just had a fantasy film to tell you about
就是我剛剛有一張幻想片跟大家講
passing through the food chain or passing through excrement
透過食物鏈的傳遞或是排泄物的傳遞
You may have these so-called drug-resistant bacteria in your body
你可能在你的身體裡面就這些所謂的抗藥性的細菌產生了
Then the bacteria are very troublesome, that is to say
那這個細菌很麻煩就是說
There are very few so-called antibiotics for muscle now to treat it
現在肌肉很少有所謂的抗生物可以去治療它
may be more troublesome in the future
將來可能更加麻煩
The other one is that you may still remember the TV of the player in the history where the player in the history had a salsa
另外一個就是大家可能還記得史上玩家有一個莎莎的那個史上玩家的電視
He had a cameraman shot in India before
他之前有一個攝影師在印度被槍擊
After the shooting, when he was sent to China for treatment, he was found to have an MDM1 bacterium on his body
槍擊後來後來再送到國內治療的時候發現他身上有一個MDM1的細菌
MDM1 and MDM1 Bacterial Infection
MDM1的一個還有MDM1的細菌的感染
He said that MDM1 was scared to death and now there are probably only two types of resistance that can treat him
他說嚇死了MDM1現在目前大概只有兩種抗爭數可以治療他
Therefore, the current environment where humans are more enlightened is the emergence of more and more drug-resistant bacteria
所以現在目前人類越明道的環境是越來越多的抗藥性的一個細菌的產生
This is our own in the laboratory, we talk to the doctors in the laboratory and colleagues in the laboratory
這是我們自己在實驗室我們跟實驗室的博士和博士實驗室的同仁
We ask all of us to report
我們請求我們大家也跟大家報告一下
In the whole process of reporting to you just now, we learned from aquatic organisms
在整個從剛剛跟大家報告的過程裡面我們從水生生物裡面
Originally, we discovered fish disease problems from aquatic residue farming.
本來是從水殘養殖裡面我們發現有魚病的問題
We want to solve the fish disease and want to replace the traditional aquatic residue farming which uses resistance data
魚病我們就想解決想要取代傳統的水殘養殖裡面使用抗爭數
Inside the traditional aquaculture
傳統的水殘養殖裡面
Use some chemical reagents to cure stupidity
使用一些化學試劑去治療愚病
Then we found out that fish is actually a very interesting thing
然後我們發現魚其實是一個很有趣的東西
There is something like an antibacterial state in the fish that produces
在魚裡面有一種類似抗菌態的東西產生
Of course, there is a so-called antibacterial state in the human body
當然在人類的身體裡面有所謂抗菌態
However, the experimental results we have done so far
但是到一直到目前我們做的實驗結果
We discovered an antimicrobial state that we can't find in fish
我們發現我們在魚類找不到的抗菌態
Its bactericidal ability appears to be greater than some of the antibacterial states found above in humans
它的殺菌能力似乎比人類上面找到的某些抗菌態
Also excellent, the bactericidal effect is better
還優 殺菌效果更好
So we can ask for a future
所以我們可以要一期的將來
we already know
我們這樣已經知道
We can probably know that in 2007
我們大概可以知道說在2007年
We found this antibacterial state
我們找到這一個抗菌態
This antimicrobial status is found on meal fish
食飯魚上面找到這個抗菌態
I just reported to you
剛有跟大家報告
Sum Ya 19 years
蘇姆牙19年
We expect in 2027
我們期望在2027年
We hope to push it to the clinic
我們希望能夠推到臨床去
But the process of these 20 years
但是這20年的過程
We may need to go through countless failures
我們可能需要經歷無數的失敗
can be extended to the entire process
才能夠推展到整個流程
Only then can we go to the clinical test in the so-called space
才能走到所謂的空間那個臨床測試
This is our vision for the future
這是我們未來的願景
I also hope that all the gentlemen and ladies here today
也希望今天在座的所有的先生女士們
In the future, expect to be in 15 years or 20 years
將來期望在15年20年
Then we can see clinically that it is such a drug
然後我們可以在臨床上看到對是這樣一個藥物
so i just told you
所以我剛剛跟大家講
There is already such a drug in 2015
2015年已經有這樣的一個藥品
Emerging FDA has recognized an antibiotic that can be marketed
新興的 FDA 已經承認可以上市的一個抗生素
A new type of antibiotic
新型的一個抗生素
In the past ten or twenty years, no emerging antibiotics have emerged
這過去這十幾年、二十幾年都沒有新興的抗生素產生
But only in the last two years has this new antibiotic been produced
但是最近這兩年才有這一種新的抗生素產生
We hope this is the Sikama company
我們希望這是 Sikama 公司
We are currently selling all kinds of anti-hospital tires
目前有在賣我們十般有的抗院胎
it serves as a raw material
它當作一個原料
You can see that the Sikama company also has a number with it
你可以看到這 Sikama 公司還跟它編了一個號碼
SMML0013
SMML0013
This is our anti-hospital tire
這是我們十般有上面的抗院胎
It has a lot of references listed above
上面它有列很多的參考文獻
All are the result of research and development in our laboratory
全部都是我們實驗室的研發的成果
You can go to the Sikama website if you are interested
你們可以如果大家有興趣可以上 Sikama 這個網站
Enter the name EBCIN
輸入這個名字 EBCIN
EBIECIDIN
EBIECIDIN
You can see that a product like ours is in the pharmaceutical factory of Sikama
就可以看到我們這樣的一個產物在 Sikama 的藥廠裡面
There is a listing for them on sale
有列為他們一個清單在賣
So Meng Yang hopes that this drug can become similar to this 1.4.1 in 20 years.
所以孟陽20年以後希望這一個藥物可以變成類似這個1.4.1
To help humans solve the problem of drug resistance
來協助人類解決抗藥性的問題
Of course I have to thank many students in my laboratory
那當然我必須要非常感謝我實驗室的很多的學生
For example, Dr. Ding Zong, he is my doctor
譬如說丁總博士,他是我的博士
There is also Dr. Huang Anning, who is a business opportunity consultant.
還有黃安寧博士,商量商機師他做的
It seems that Dr. Ding did it.
看來是丁總博士做的
In addition, Jay Ang is an Indian student who is doing Youmenlu group induction
另外還有傑昂是做優門卢群感應一個印度的學生
There is also Dr. Pan Jieyi
另外還有一個潘傑裔博士
He is now at Gaohua University of Science and Technology of China
他現在在高中華人科技大學
He was experimenting with tumors in dogs
他是做狗的腫瘤的實驗
And Mr. Jian Jixian also assisted us in the tumor experiment of dogs.
還有簡紀憲老師也是協助我們做狗的腫瘤實驗
There are other teachers Xu Junsheng and Li Xianping who will be in the future respectively
還有其他徐俊生老師跟李賢平老師分別將來在
Our development of anti-drugs will play a very important role
我們做抗藥物上面的發展會扮演一個很重要的角色
Of course the most important
當然最重要的
We are currently doing experiments with pigs
我們目前在做豬的實驗
It is all in cooperation with Mr. Wu Hongyi of Pingtung University of Science and Technology
完全都是跟屏東科技大學的吳宏毅老師合作
The pig experiment depends on him
那豬的實驗都要靠他
Because he has a beneficiary license
因為他有受益師執照
Because there are many things that can help us experiment
因為很多事情可以幫我們做實驗
You just saw it
那剛剛大家有看到了
In fact, at the beginning, Wu acted as an anti-court
其實剛開始起吳做抗院態的
anti-animals
抗院態動物
The animal experiment teacher should be my junior
那動物實驗的老師應該是我的學弟
He should be younger than me by two years
他應該小我一點還兩年
Teacher Wu Zhangze
吳彰澤老師
He is Mr. Wu Zhangze from the Department of Teachers, Ocean University
他是海洋大學師柄系的吳彰澤老師
Back when I didn't know how to do animal experiments
那我當初不會做動物實驗的時候
I'm totally going to ask him to help me
我完全都是去請他來協助我
conduct similar animal experiments
進行類似的動物實驗
Including if you see burns or
包括你們看到燒燙傷或是
Uber Luoxuan's induction experiment
Uber羅軒感應的實驗
This is Huang Anning
這是黃岸寧
I especially want to show his photo today
我今天特別要秀一下他的照片
Because usually when we say thank you
因為平常我們在做感謝的時候
maybe only the name
可能只有名字念過去了
Everyone doesn't know what he looks like
大家都不知道他長什麼樣子
you'll see he can ask him some questions
你會看到他可以跟他問些問題
Huang Anning is excellent
黃岸寧他很優秀
He got last year and the year before
他拿到了去年還前年
Received the Outstanding Postdoctoral Research Award from the Ministry of Science and Technology
拿到科技部的傑出博士後研究獎
this is a rare award
這是很難得的一個獎
He seems to be out of blue and Sheng Yilan
他好像青出藍跟盛宜藍
Because I have not yet received the Outstanding Research Award from the Ministry of Science and Technology
因為我都還沒有拿到科技部的傑出研究獎
He has already received the postdoctoral outstanding research award from the Ministry of Science and Technology
他已經先拿到科技部的博士後傑出研究獎
The other one is Dr. Pan Jieyi
那另外一個是潘傑義博士
He's a tumor for a dog
他就是做狗的腫瘤
fat like this
胖胖的這樣子
Then our full time is the latest photoshoot
然後我們全時間是最近的照相
Dress a little more tiresome
穿得比較拉胎一點
Then this is Dr. Ding Zhenghong, this is his wife who just got married this year
然後這是丁正宏博士,這是他今年才結婚的太太
Then Dr. Ding Zhenghong is doing the experiment of three-one into five cancers, and recently he is doing the experiment of lung cancer
然後丁正宏博士就是在做那個三一進五癌的實驗,還有最近在做肺癌的實驗
Then we recently thought of an excellent model experiment for the treatment of lung cancer
那我們最近也想到一個絕佳的治療肺癌的一個模式的實驗
I hope that in 15 or 20 years from now, it will become an emerging drug for the treatment of lung cancer.
希望將來也是在15、20年以後,希望成為一個新興治療肺癌的藥物
Then I am now at 8:16, and within a minute of my post, I will tell you about my current working environment
那我現在8點16分,我大概發一分鐘內,我跟大家講我現在目前工作的環境
This is the Linhai Research Station of the Institute of Cell and Biology of the Biamine Research Institute
這是雙胺研究院細胞與各理生物學研究所林海研究站
The Institute of Cellular and Physiological Biology has now been transformed
現在已經改造細胞與各理生物學研究所
It was my professor Zhihao at the beginning, today the teacher is sitting here today
當初是我的志好教授,今天老師今天坐在這邊
At the beginning, Mr. Wu was in charge of coordinating the former head of Youxi Space County
當初是由吳老師去協調當初的游錫空間縣長
And the chairman of Jinche came to donate this land
還有金車的董事長來捐贈這塊地的
Then the reminder this time was mentioned by Dean Li Yanzhe, very beautiful Lin Hai Research Station
那這次提示是李演哲院長所提的,很漂亮林海研究站
I think it's really good to do research there, but I don't understand why many students don't come
我覺得在那邊做研究真的很好,但是我搞不清楚為什麼很多學生都不來
If you also ask high school students every night, we will meet with six universities, and we will come to our Linhai Research Station
如果大家天晚也拜託高中生,我們見六大學,我們來我們林海研究站
We are researching in Linhai, saving lives regardless of each other
我們在臨海研究,救人不分彼此
This seaside study is beautiful inside
這個臨海研究在裡面很漂亮
At the beginning, when I went from England in 1992
剛開始我從英國92年去的時候
In fact, there is nothing but light here
其實這邊光通通的,全部都沒有什麼
But now it's tree fuyin
但現在是樹木浮陰
There's a small fountain here
這邊有一個小噴水池
this is a beautiful environment
這是很漂亮的環境
This was taken when the sun was shining
這是太陽好的時候拍的
You don't see when the sun is bad and the storm is stormy
你們沒有看到太陽不好狂風暴雨的時候
It's even scarier when it's a typhoon
颱風天氣的時候更可怕
Because there are no tall buildings near us to go alone
因為我們附近都沒有高的建築去獨黨
so you can see the little gusts of those trees
所以你可以看到那些樹木的小狂風
Afraid of the sun
怕太陽
Then our seaside research in the whole structure
然後我們這次臨海研究在整個架構
You can see that there is a water and sky supply system here
可以看到這邊有水天供應系統
We are here to do experiments
做實驗我們是在這邊
Then here is the dormitory with students or assistants
然後這邊是宿舍有學生或是助理
When I first went there, the students were actually quite afraid of me.
剛開始去的時候其實學生蠻怕我的
Because I was only in my thirties at the time
因為我那時候才三十幾歲有去的時候
I am very happy to get up at 8 o'clock in the morning to do experiments
很高興早上起來八點多就起來做實驗
Before the student came, I kicked his door
學生還沒有來,我就踹他的門
so i want to thank my students so much for being there with me
所以我要非常感謝我那些學生從人在那邊跟我陪我度過的
Many students who do research years
很多做研究歲月的學生
This very good place is what idea we thought of
這個很好的地方就是我們想到什麼idea
Immediately, you can go in there to do experiments on aquatic life.
馬上可以進去那邊做水生生物的實驗
There are farms here, very good farms
這邊都是養殖場,很好的一個養殖場
gene transfer experiments
可以做基因傳職實驗
That's what the vice president just said
那就是剛剛副院長講到
Our laboratory has cooperated with Mr. Wu Jingqiao
我們實驗室有跟吳京橋老師合作
Then carry out the research and development of the so-called fluorescent fish
然後進行所謂的那個螢光魚的研發
Well, I didn't focus on fluorescent fish today.
那我今天重點並沒有要講螢光魚
Actually, the glowfish is another question.
其實螢光魚是另外一個題
Because I just told him that aquatic animals can get sick
因為我剛剛有跟他講水產生物會生病
So we hope that this aquatic organism has anti-smoke expression
所以我們就希望這個水生生物上面都有抗菸態表達
That's because I don't know if you've ever raised fish
那因為我不知道你們有沒有養過魚
I'm an ornamental fish. I bought ornamental fish when I was in college.
我觀賞魚我從年在大學的時候去買觀賞魚
The ornamental fish, let's say five of them, sell me 200 yuan?
那觀賞魚譬如說五隻賣我兩百塊嗎
College students are poor, you should know
大學生很窮你們要知道
Don't snatch college students for two hundred yuan, it's easy
不要搶養大學生兩百塊很簡單
High school students are also very poor. Two hundred yuan is a lot
高中生也是很窮嘛兩百塊很多
Well, I bought it and raised it for a week
好,買一買就養了一個禮拜
If he hung up on me, I went to the boss and said
他魚給我掛了我就去找老闆說
what does he wash
他要洗什麼
He said that when he cleaned his teeth, he would wash his back and his head would be thick.
他說洗牙就洗了跟背頭厚
Well, then buy it, I bought it for a week and then hung it up for me
那好啦,那買一買我買了一個禮拜以後又給我掛了
then i will go to the boss
那我再去找老闆
That boss has been bred by me in Silin one
那老闆已經被我繁殖在四林的一個
water hog jar know how to do it later
水豬罐 之後就知道怎麼做
I'll say water pig give me some more fish
我會說 水豬 再給我一些魚
I was wondering why the fish died every time I bought them back for a week
我在想為什麼魚每次給我買回去養一個禮拜就掛了
Then I thought that after I become a teacher now
後來就想著我現在當老師以後
After I worked as a research scholar
我在當研究工作學者以後
I can keep this fish alive longer
我能夠讓這個魚活久一點
so i just go with that
所以我就跟那個
At that time, we wanted to say that anti-pregnancy
那時候我們就想說把抗孕胎
The transplantation is using the microscopic life-assisted mode, so that he can produce anti-pregnancy even after lifting the table
移植在用顯微助生模式讓他在提表都可以產生抗孕胎
Then the fish will not be infected by bacteria
那這個魚就不會受到細菌感染了
He can fight bacteria
他可以抗就細菌
However, this is only one of the main points
然而這個只是其中一個要點
Fish will not get sick as we are curators with the main purpose
魚不會生病不如我們當館長與主要目的
you may have forgotten
大家可能忘記了
Because what we just talked about now is to use the synthetic ecology to do it.
因為現在我們剛剛講的都是用合成的生態下去做
Synthetic ecology has troubles and the price is high
合成生態有的麻煩價格很高
The student just told me
剛剛那個學生有跟我講
Huang Hanming told me
黃漢明有跟我講說
98% of EPI costs 780 US dollars per gram
98%的EPI一克要780塊美金
So one gram is 100 people, Miliguang costs 780 US dollars
所以一克就是100個人密利光要780塊美金
I personally feel
我個人覺得
may still be a bit expensive
可能還是有點貴
So we want to use fish
所以我們就想要用魚
You know that fish is warm
你們知道那魚殘暖
Sometimes there are hundreds of thousands of broken pieces
有時候一殘就十幾萬顆
it's scary, isn't it?
很嚇人對不對
soft sea tactics
軟海戰術
So we want to be able to get from its
所以我們就希望能夠從它的
its that warm
它的那個殘暖的
In the residual heat process
殘暖過程裡面
In the future, these anti-halo
將來可以把這些抗暈
it also extracts
它也給提煉出來
Because now it's easy to do protein expression
因為現在做蛋白質表達很簡單
Then you must be curious to ask me
那你們一定很好奇問我
Why don't you use a colon induction?
為什麼不用大腸感應就好了
Because high school or college students
因為高中生或大學生
I have a speech today
今天有來提言講
or friends online
或是在網路上的朋友
you are on the internet
你們在網路上
should ask me this question
應該會問我這個問題
Why not use colon induction
為什麼不要用大腸感應
or as we express the system
或是像我們去表達系統
there are many things now
現在有很多事情
indescribable
一言難盡
we are also doing
我們也在做
Trying hard to do colon induction
很努力的做大腸感應
Anti-stunning
但是有效果的抗暈態
Basically it shows
基本上它表現出來
would kill yourself to behave
會殺了自己表現的
that gut feeling
那個大腸感應
this is very troublesome
這是很麻煩的事情
but if fish
但是如果用魚
fish it doesn't show it
魚它並不會把它表現出來
protein
蛋白質
expressed protein
表現出來的蛋白質
won't kill the fish
並不會把這個魚給殺掉
look how happy it is
你看它活得多高興
how fast it shines
發亮發得多快
so we are probably
所以我們大概是
The original idea of doing anti-response posture, there are probably two kinds of ideas
做抗應態當初的想法 構思大概有這兩種
I hope you will buy it back later
就希望大家買回去以後
call later
以後播歪歪叫
students are poor
又去學生很窮
200 yuan is really a lot
200塊真的很多
This time we have genetically transferred equipment at the Linhai Research Station is very beautiful
這次我們在林海研究站基因轉職的設備很漂亮
In the whole of Taiwan, there was no gene transfer in Qigu
在全台灣當初在旗鼓還沒有基因轉職
Field testing is also very missed when
田間測試也很錯失的時候
The Linhai Research Station should cover all of Asia
林海研究站應該是全亞洲
Or the most advanced genetically modified job in all of Taiwan or all of Asia
或是全台灣或全亞洲最先進的一個基因轉職的
Don't be afraid of anything running out
大家不用怕什麼東西跑出去
or a problem with field testing
或田間測試有問題
It's still the same now we have a lot of that
現在還是一樣我們有很多的那個
the interception system or the processing system
那個攔截系統或是處理系統
Then the genetic transfer at the Linhai Research Station just started
那這個林海研究站剛開始的基因轉職
It's all beautiful now
現在都刷得很漂亮
A very modern testing ground
都非常的現代化的一個試驗場
In the end, I still want to thank you all
那最後我還是要謝謝你們大家
I spent so much time listening to me today
今天花了那麼多時間來聽我講
I wish you all the best of health
也希望要先祝大家整體健康萬事如意
The most important thing is to welcome you all when you are free
最重要有空歡迎你們大家
Come to Linhai Research Station to give us encouragement
來林海研究站給我們鼓勵打氣
of course to encourage
當然要鼓勵
Someone needs to be more willing, especially a graduate student
要有人更有意願,尤其是研究生
Welcome to our inspiration research station to do research
歡迎來我們靈感研究站做研究
Then I know that there may be some pharmaceutical companies interested in investing on the Internet
然後我知道在網路上可能有一些有興趣的投資的藥廠
Please come and talk to us about our accounting
請來跟我們共用事務組計轉事談我們的計轉
Then how to help us develop
然後怎麼樣協助我們開發
At least don't make me 15 or 20 years, just make me dead for 15 years
至少不要讓我15、20年能夠讓我木個15年就好了
Then help everyone to be more promising on some antibacterial effects
然後協助大家能夠在一些抗菌的效果上面能夠更有展望
Thanks
謝謝
Thank you, thank you very much Dr. Chen for a very wonderful presentation
謝謝 非常謝謝陳博士非常精彩的演講
Then I wonder if you have anything to ask Dr. Chen about?
那我想各位有沒有什麼要請教陳博士的事情
later
後面
The anti-Qing platform is the one that is moving overnight
那個抗菁台就是說是在移的那個連夜延
Just to avoid that leftover field
就是為了避免那個遺花野
Does that mean
那是不是就是說
A chair that lives where the night is cloudy
生活在夜混濁的地方的椅子
It may find that the more powerful the viewing platform
它可能會發現那看鏡台的威力會越強
like a mud mound or something
比如說泥丘或什麼樣
Would it be better than being in a stone pound chair
會不會比在石磅椅裡面
this theory is good
這個理論很好
but i don't know
可是我不知道
Because I only feel that the whole fish
因為我只覺得整個魚
This should be in terms of evolution
這應該要從演化上面來講
Because the whole fish evolution process
因為整個魚的演化過程裡面
i can't tell you
我並不能夠告訴你說
Do you live in the dirty water at night?
是不是生活在夜污濁的水裡面
Although I just said
雖然我剛剛有講
But that's universal
但是那是值普遍性的
if it is like this
如果是這樣的話
I think the fish in our Sifenxi should be more resistant
我覺得我們四分溪的魚應該更耐
There should be many
原來應該有很多的
Everyone seems to see a sign
大家好像我看了一個牌子
No arrest, right?
不准捕抓嘛對不對
At present, it is just looking for ecology from Mimisheng
那目前只是從蜜蜜生上去找生態
Or other animals have early
或者是別的動物也有盡早
that's the first question
那這個是第一個問題
The second question is to say
第二個問題就是說
Ecology Can Kill Morbidity
生態可以殺死病境症情
Will it affect normal cells?
他對於正常細胞會不會有影響
The third one seems to me that I heard you said that in that
第三個好像我聽說您說在那個
So far, it has not been formally used in humans
目前就是還沒有正式在人體上用
like this
就好像是這個
But I seem to have heard on the Internet that there are direct sellers selling this product
但是我在網路上好像有聽到有直銷的在賣這個生災
don't know you know what this is all about
不曉得您知道這是什麼一回事
do you have a problem
你問題有問題嗎
Anti-morbid at certain concentrations
抗病態在某種濃度
above a certain concentration
某一個濃度以上
It will be normal cells will be destroyed according to the disaster
它會正常細胞會災掉 照災
kill normal cells
照樣殺正常細胞
so we usually
所以我們通常
I'm giving a popular science speech today
我今天因為是科普演講
So I didn't spend a lot of time fixing it here
所以我沒有把很多時間結果修在這裡
we have a few in the lab
我們在實驗室裡面有幾個
So if students or researchers in our lab
所以如果學生或是研究工作者在我們實驗室
We will first test for cytotoxicity
我們會先測細胞毒性
this is the first step
這是第一個步驟
The second step is when it comes time to develop the drug
第二個步驟就是要發展藥物的時候
to test some of its body
要測它的一些身體
Like GOTGPT or those things, see what dosage is best
比如說GOTGPT或那些東西,看什麼樣的劑量是最好
This answers your first question, his political cells are toxic, there is nothing wrong
這回答你第一個問題,他的政壤細胞是有毒性的,沒有錯
But Dependent still depends on different anti-pathological conditions, I have read some reports
但是Dependent在還是要看不同的抗病態,我有看過一些報告
Some antipathogens are non-cytotoxic
有一些抗病態是沒有細胞毒性的
But he has the function of so-called cellular immune regulation
但是他有所謂的細胞免疫調節的功能
Its bactericidal effect is not that strong
他殺菌的效果並不是那麼強
Usually less toxic means that its ability to kill bacteria is not so strong
通常比較沒有毒性的代表他殺菌的能力並不是那麼強
So we have to adjust a very good dosage, just like you take Kangshengsu
所以我們必須要調整一個很好的劑量,就像你吃康生素一樣
You also have to find a good dose
你也必須要找到一個很好的劑量
Excessive health vitamins can also cause
過量的康生素也會引起你身體裡面
bad situation happens
不好的情況產生
right
對不對
The second problem is that I forgot
第二個問題是我忘記了
do you mind talking to me again
你介意再跟我講
It seems that the Internet is selling that thing in the market
就是市面上好像網路有在賣那個東西
I don't know how to answer this question
這個問題我不知道要怎麼回答
because i told you
因為我跟你們報告你
In fact, you can see that Sikamai is also sold in the market
其實可以看到Sikamai也在市面上賣了
You can buy our anti-momentum
你是可以買得到我們的抗運態
Yes, it is for sale
對,是可以賣
But let me say one more thing
但是,我再講一件事
In fact, ten years ago, when I was in the anti-mobility posture,
其實十幾年前我做抗運態的時候
At that time, there were not many people in the world doing anti-movement
那時候全世界做抗運態沒有很多人
not not many people
不是沒有很多人
It is in Japan, mainland China, Taiwan, Southeast Asian countries
就是在日本、大陸、台灣、東南亞國家
These Asian countries do not have a lot of manpower to go
這些亞洲國家並沒有很大量的人力下去
Mainland China's anti-transportation attitude is really poisonous
中國大陸做抗運態真的是如果有毒毒
I heard they have become a special zone to do anti-movement
我聽說他們已經成了一個特區再做抗運態
So they called an anti-motion state Sikobon
所以他們把一個抗運態叫Sikobon
It is the anti-motion state obtained on the forehead
就是額上面得到的抗運態
Has been sold to the so-called Tianjian toilet
已經賣到所謂的田尖廁
Tian Jian went down
田尖下去了
can be bought
可以買得到
yes , so i am a little worried too
對,所以我也有一點擔心
Will there be waist resistance in the future?
將來是不是有抗腰性的情況產生
yes it is available for purchase
對,這是可以買得到的
but that's not
但是那個不是
no
不是
Not American DA or Taiwan
不是美國的DA或是台灣的
Taiwan's Drug Inspection Bureau has licensed it to be sold in the form of drugs
台灣的藥檢局許可以藥物的形式下去賣的
Like we went to buy from Sikama
就像我們去跟Sikama買
It's just a substance sold to you
它只是一個物質而已賣給你
No one can control how you use it
你要怎麼用其實也沒有人能夠管
Ask for advice
請教教說
just saw that on video
剛在影片上有看到那個
Fish with cancer in antibacterial water
有換癌症的魚在抗菌態水裡
That cancerous tumor can disappear
那個癌腫瘤可以消失
This means that the antibacterial state can cure cancer
這樣就表示抗菌態可以治癌
so should we eat more fish
所以我們是不是要多吃魚
But the fish is different from the fish you just had
不過魚跟你剛的蝕班魚之外
Do other fish also have antibacterial properties?
別的魚類是不是也有抗菌態
Thanks
謝謝
i just said
我剛有講
Antibacterial water is also present in your body
抗菌態水在你的身體裡面也有
but we don't eat people
但我們不會吃人
We eat fish for
我們吃魚的目的是
It is hoped that in the future through the process of aquaculture
希望將來能夠透過在水產養殖過程
I have another interesting story for you
我另外一個有趣的故事我收給你聽
Some people are collecting what I just said
有一部分的人他們在蒐集就是我剛講的
Isn't everyone immune to fishing?
大家摸魚不是有免疫嗎?
Some people are collecting fish immunity
有一些人在蒐集魚的免疫
Then he took it as a sort of antibacterial substance
然後他把它當作一個類似抗菌的物質
down to do business
下去做買賣
then all fish will have an antibacterial status
那所有的魚都會有抗菌態
As far as I can tell since you're not eating fish
據我既然目前包括你吃的不是魚
is aquatic organisms
就是水產生物
So that oyster will also have an antibacterial status
所以說那個母蠣也會有抗菌態
But among all the fish species
但是在這所有的魚種裡面
Why do I especially choose grouper and silky fish
為什麼我特別選石斑魚跟烏骨魚
Because grouper and blackbone are very important aquaculture industries in Taiwan
因為石斑魚跟烏骨魚是台灣很重要的一個水產養殖產業
I hope that the process of giving a speech today is not just about
我希望今天出來演講的過程不是只有講
We use the antibacterial state to do it in medical medicine
我們用抗菌態做在醫療醫學上面
I also want to let everyone know
我也希望能夠讓大家知道
Aquaculture is actually Taiwan's inherent aquaculture such as grouper and black bone fish
水產養殖其實台灣固有的水產養殖這種石斑魚跟烏骨魚
A breed that has been in Taiwan for so long
在台灣已經那麼久的一個養殖的
The industry also hopes to attract everyone's attention
產業也希望引起大家的關注
Later you go out on the street
以後你們出去街上
Please choose more of these kinds of juban fish and five countries fish to eat
請多選選這種十番魚跟五國魚來吃
The multi-selected juban fish and five countries fish to eat
多選的這種十番魚跟五國魚來吃
It can also promote the vigorous development of our flood farming industry
也可以促使我們水災養殖的產業更蓬勃發展
They all eat the fish bred by this Shuizi sheep
都吃這個水子羊羊殖的魚
Are you eating too much healthy food?
會不會吃盡太多康生食
fish in water
水裡面養殖的魚
In fact, the government now does so-called barcode tracking
其實現在政府有做所謂的條碼追蹤
I don't know that you actually learned from the process of the ten-fish industry
我不知道您其實從十番魚產業的過程裡面
As long as you are in Taipei Agricultural Products
你只要在台北農產
It has a similar
它上面有一個類似
Similar to that black Q barcode
類似那個什麼黑Q條碼
According to the future it will have a production history
按照以後它就會有生產履歷
Tell you which factory this fish came from
告訴你這隻魚是從哪一個廠裡面出來的
Then it seems that it will also test whether the fish has health vitamins
然後它好像也會有測試這隻魚生產有沒有康生素
The government is actually doing a good job of checking the gates now.
政府其實現在把關拔得很好
That's just something I remember happening before some decamp farms
那只是我記得之前發生一些十番魚養殖廠
It seems that there is no way through this system
好像是沒有透過這個系統
However, it was found to contain
但是被驗出裡面含有
Many chemicals or antibiotics
很多的化學藥劑或是抗生素
So I still encourage everyone to eat more fish
所以我還是鼓勵大家多吃魚
Please trust Taiwanese aquaculture farmers
請務必相信台灣的水產養殖的養殖戶
Let's see if Yuntai cooks it
看運泰煮了以後是不是會
It's also an interesting question
這也是一個很有趣的問題
recently
最近
The deputy dean asked an interesting question
副院長問到一個有趣的問題
Do you all want to eat fish after fighting the Taizhu?
抗應太主以後你們大家要吃魚嗎
I also encourage everyone to eat more fish today
我今天也鼓勵大家多吃魚
Will there be no small children in the future after resisting the Taizhu?
抗應太主以後會不會沒有小
Just cook at 100 degrees C
就是100度C煮
Only recently did this result
最近才把這個結果做出來
And published on PoS1
並且發表在PoS1上面
After cooking at 100 degrees C, when you did not cook
煮100度C以後本來你沒有煮的時候
About double the MIC will kill bacteria
大概是一倍的MIC會殺菌
After cooking, it still has the effect of killing bacteria
煮了以後它還是有殺菌的效果
We have an anti-response too
我們手上有一個抗應太
very interesting
挺有趣的
so we just saw that
所以我們剛剛看到那個
That TP4 that can heal the beautiful feeling
可以治療優美的感覺那個TP4
you know the acid in the stomach is sour
你知道胃裡面的酸很酸
PH4 or something
PH4什麼的
But it still has bactericidal ability in acidic environment
但它在酸性的環境它照樣有殺菌能力
10 minutes to 60 minutes
煮過10分鐘還60分鐘
It still has a bactericidal effect
它還是有殺菌的效果
We put it in the Vickers tube, put it in the water and boil it for a hundred degrees, instead of closing the whole water
我們就把他放在維氏管裡面,放在水裡面煮一百度溪,不是整個水關下去
Just put it in two Vickers tubes and let him cook like this
就是放在維氏兩管裡面,讓他煮這樣子
Turns out he's still active, which I find interesting
結果他還是有活性,我覺得蠻有趣的
So we want to know that under normal conditions, Teacher Xu Junzhen is actually a teacher from National Taiwan University
所以我們想要知道說,在普通的狀態之下,徐俊珍老師其實那邊就是台大的一個老師
He was before, before he had the whole structure of doing anti-motion
他之前是,之前他有做抗運態的整個結構
He has made the structure under long-term temperature, but I have not told him what kind of changes will happen to the structure after being cooked for a hundred times.
他有做在長溫之下的結構,但是我還沒有跟他講,一百度溪煮完以後幫我做結構產生什麼樣的變化
Why does it still have the ability to sterilize bacteria, listen up
為什麼還有殺菌的能力,聽進去
Hello, that is, I have seen one before, which is vitamin D, which can improve the body's anti-mobility effect
你好,就是我之前有看過一個就是維生素D,他可以提高人體抗運態的作用
Is this true?
請問這是真的嗎?
why? thanks
為什麼?謝謝
Vincent book D?
文生書D喔?
Yes, Vincent Shu D
對,文生書D
Then Pei Baowang published it in the series with the prefix N?
那裴寶王在N字頭的系列發表的吧?
I have seen a similar article, but I did not read carefully
我有看過類似那一篇,但是我沒有仔細看
this question...
這問題...
I don't know either
我也不知道
you ask me like this
你問到我這樣
Teacher Bao Wang D can help me add
寶王D老師可以幫我補充一下
I can guess, because general antibiotics...
我可以猜啊,因為一般抗生...
Which paragraph does this follow?
這個都按哪一段
right
對
General antibiotics its structure
一般抗生素它的結構
just... sorry
就是...對不起
This antibiotic has no specific structure for its structure
這種抗生素它的結構是沒有特定的結構
But when it encounters the state of Zilong sex
可是它碰到紫龍性的狀態的時候
It will be easier to appear as it just said
它會比較容易顯成它剛講
Two sides... that is, one side is Zilong sex
雙面...也就一邊是紫龍性
One side is the structure on the front
一邊是在正面的結構
Also in the time of pure water dragon sex
也就在純水龍性的時候
It is not this structure
它是不會這個結構
Then encounter...Wen Shengshu D's purple dragon...
那碰到...文生書D這種紫龍性的...
Or the environment of Zilong sex
或者紫龍性的環境一下
It is easy to show that the effective structure
它很容易顯成那種有效的那種結構
So relatively its bactericidal ability will be better
所以相對的它的殺菌能力會比較好
Go ahead... also for us...
繼續...也就針對我們...
Our understanding of antibacterial ecology is like this
我們這個對抗菌生態了解是這樣
Just mentioned the heating issue
剛提到加熱的問題
In fact, this protein is a structure of more than 20 amino acids
實際上這個蛋白質它是一個二十幾個胺基酸的結構
Assuming that because its structure is originally no structure
假設說因為它結構本來是沒有結構
Only when encountering this environment will the structure
要碰到這個環境才會結構
So after you group it, its structure is messed up
所以你把它組掉以後它結構是亂掉
But when it encounters a child-like environment
可是當它碰到子龍性的環境的時候
it structure comes back
它結構又回來
So maybe this can be explained by
所以可能這樣可以解釋說
Why is it still active after grouping
為什麼組完它還有活性原因
that just mentioned
那剛剛提到就是說
if you eat this
這個東西你吃下去的話
May be hydrolyzed by my stomach acid
可能會被我胃酸水解掉
Of course it won't help
那當然就沒救了
But stomach acid is what I just
不過胃酸是就是我剛剛
that I guessed next is
那個我接著料掉是
We just made that time mention
我們剛剛做的那個時間提提
It is in the sour environment that it has
就是在酸心環境它有
In the process of the protein not working
那個蛋白質沒的作用過程裡面
It still retains the activity of its MIC
它還是保有它MIC的活性
So now we are surprised
所以我們現在就是很訝異
why does it have that activity
它為什麼會有那個活性
after the group
就是組了以後
Either in an acid environment or a subtractive environment
或是在酸性環境或是減性的環境
We have done B 2 to 14
我們有做過B學2到14
24,6,80,12,14
24,6,80,12,14
We found between 4 and 12
我們發現在4到12之間
it still holds
它還是保有
After being released in a private yard for a period of time
放了以後在私人院放了一段時間以後
He still picks it up to make MIC, he still has the energy to sterilize
他還是拿起來做MIC 他還是有殺菌的能量
we have done recently
我們最近有做
very interesting
挺有趣的
I do not know why either
我也不知道為什麼
Maybe it's really similar to what Mr. Liao Wenwei said
可能真的類似廖文維老師講的
Hello, teacher
老師你好
I want to ask you a question
我一個問題想請教你
i saw the dog test
我看到那個狗的試驗
After he beat him in with that MAS
他用那個MAS 把他打進去之後
We saw that the teacher still has
我們看到老師那裡面還有
Do the treatment in Bless Cancer
做Bless Cancer 裡面的治療
Does he have the same plan like this
是不是他有相同的這樣子一個計畫說
Let women's Bless Cancer
讓婦女的Bless Cancer 當中
He was hired by MVT
他是MVT 請掉的
Does he have the same effect
是不是他有相同的一個效果
If this treatment
如果說這樣治療的話
he is a little scary
他有一點恐怖
Is there such a plan
有沒有這樣子一個規劃
What kind of treatment is his treatment
他那個治療是怎樣一個治療法
that kind of dog
狗那個種有
he's actually quite funny
他其實挺有趣的
because we are experimenting with rats
因為我們在老鼠試驗
we're on cell experiments
我們在細胞試驗上面
we actually feel
我們其實覺得
The antibacterial tires you just saw
那個你剛剛看到那幾個抗菌胎
it is the way to go the cell statue
它是走細胞雕像的路
but you see in animals
但是你在動物身上看到
In fact, there is data similar to cell necrosis
其實那個有一類似是細胞壞死的data
so we
所以我們
At that time, I didn't go down to ask
那時候並沒有下去追問說
exist...
在...
Because it is very troublesome in Taiwan
因為在台灣很麻煩一件事
It's a dog experiment
就是做狗的實驗
Our dog is not
我們那個狗其實不是
Everyone imagines it made with beagle
大家想像用米格魯做的
Because when we made this plan
因為當初我們這個計畫做的時候
COA said that if we use beagle to make
農委會說如果我們用米格魯做
It absolutely swallowed up our plan.
它就絕對把我們這個計畫給吞當了
I think...
我想...
So because there are...
所以因為有...
We are doing a project in that agricultural bio-type fruitamine therapy plan
我們是做在那個農業型生物型果胺療計畫裡面一個計畫
So but one thing it allows us to do is
所以但是它允許我們做一件事就是
This dog is a stray dog
這個狗是流浪狗
Or a dog brought by the master
或是有世主帶過去的狗
Those four groups can let us do this experiment with their consent
那四組在同意的情況之下可以讓我們做這個實驗
But when it came, some tumors were very large.
可是來的時候有些腫瘤都很大顆
when we call in
那我們打進去的時候
After a while that Petite
過了一段時間以後那個Petite
Because of the volume we play sometimes
因為我們打的量有時候
To be honest, it doesn't have a lot of dogs
說真的它狗的數量不是很多
So sometimes that air
所以有時候那個氣量
I think it might look a bit
我覺得現在看起來可能有些是
just overdose
就是過量
so overdose
所以過量的時候
Its anti-morbidity is actually inside the cells
它的抗病態其實在細胞裡面
I think there is really something
我覺得真的有所謂的
As the gentleman just said, it has cytotoxic effect
像剛剛那個先生講的有細胞毒殺作用
So after he killed the cells
所以他把細胞給殺掉以後
A condition that becomes necrotic
變成細胞壞死的一個情況
That's on Lu Lai
那在魯來身上
Because our family has not yet
因為我們家還沒有
We can only be Lulai on the ancestors
我們只有在老祖身上做魯來
Lu Lai, we haven't done animal experiments yet
我們還沒有做到動物實驗的魯來
because we also want to find
因為我們也想要去找
There are dogs that specialize in Lulai
有專門產生魯來的狗
or someone willing to take it to an animal hospital
或是有人願意帶到動物醫院
and then treated by a physician
然後經過受醫師診治
His dog is Lu Lai
他這隻狗是魯來
so-called trinity breast cancer
所謂的三一性乳癌
we have to wait again for this
這個我們又要再去等
So in the whole animal experiments
所以在整個動物實驗裡面
We currently have no more detailed information to tell you
我們現在目前並沒有更詳細的資料可以告訴你
But just that picture
但剛剛那個圖
The one with breast cancer and the one with breast cancer
那個乳癌附和乳癌的那個
In fact, the picture of the breast cancer is on the Internet
其實那個乳癌的圖片在網路上
We may all see
我們大家可能會可以看到
girl getting breast cancer
女孩子在得乳癌
If you accidentally get triple breast cancer
如果不小心得到三一性乳癌
And then at the end not very early on
然後到最後沒有在很早期的時候
In the end, her wound will fester
她到最後她傷口就是會有潰爛的情況產生
you can see the bones
你都可以看得到肉骨
In principle, we just hope
那我們原則上我們就是希望
hope to develop some kind of
希望發展某種
You can see that we have information about Shao Shangchang
你可以看到我們有哨上昌的資料
We want to develop some kind of paint
我們希望發展某種塗料
because it can be applied to her wounds
因為可以塗在她的傷口上
It can also close the wound and kill cancer cells
又可以讓傷口一合又可以殺癌細胞
Now we just want to do experiments like this in the future
目前我們就是將來想要做類似這樣的實驗
But the trouble with this experiment is that you have to
但是這實驗有個麻煩的地方就是要
I just reported to you
我剛剛有跟你們報告
Just to find the crooked dog
就是要找到五歪的狗
Then there's Trinity Breast Cancer again
然後又是三一性乳癌的工
Then you can't use rice to cut milk
然後又不能拿米割乳來做
so this will cost
所以這個要花
So Su Wu shepherds for 18 years
所以蘇武牧養18年
I may have to pasture for 20 years
我可能要牧20幾年
that's the factor
就是因素就這樣
To wait for
要等
Some of our experiments
我們這些實驗有些
You may have seen me talking here for less than an hour
大家可能看到我在這邊講不到一個小時
more than an hour
一個小時多
People say that one minute on stage and one minute off stage
人家說台上一分鐘台下
We've probably been doing it for ten years
我們可能已經做十幾年了
right
對
So please forgive our speed
所以請你見諒我們的速度
why so slow
為什麼還這麼慢
I also wish it could be faster
我也很希望能夠快一點
Thanks
謝謝
i want to ask
我想問一下
May I ask how much EP1 a fish will have
請問一下一隻魚會有多少EP1
It is anti bacteria peptide
就是 anti bacteria peptide
a fish
一隻魚
finish your question
對 你的問題問完
I have no idea
我不知道
that or
那或者說
If you want to get imminigrant
你們如果要拿到 imminigrant
How many fish do you need to extract to get
要萃取多少隻魚才能拿到
good question again
這問題又問得很好
We don't extract from fish
我們不是從魚身上萃取
We use the model of synthetic cards to
我們是用合成牌牌的模式來
use ecology
用生態
Ecos can now be crafted with Ecosynthesis
現在生態可以用生態合成以合成
It is a machine that can synthesize
就是一個機器可以合成
No need to kill a chicken and take its soft
不用去殺一隻雞然後取它的軟
We can use machines to synthesize ecology
我們可以用機器把生態合成出來
Excuse me
請問一下
If you eat fish
那如果吃魚
Which part do you want us to eat to be more rewarding?
你是希望我們吃哪個部分會比較有
Is it fish skin?
是吃魚皮嗎
or what to eat
還是吃什麼
good question
對 這問題問得很好
I don't know how to answer
我也不知道怎麼回答
When I first started thinking about this topic
我剛開始想這個題目的時候
I hope everyone can eat more fish in the future
我是希望大家將來能多吃魚
Then promote the development of our residual farming industry
然後促進我們隨殘養殖產業的
that kidney
那個腎性
Attracted by this topic
由這個題目吸引大家來
Know the residual farming industry
知道隨殘養殖產業
It's an interesting creature in language
在語言裡面是一個很有趣的生物
sorry i have one last question
抱歉 我再問最後一個問題
Excuse me
請問一下
If we only treat this
我們如果一隻TREAT這個
Antibacterial peptide to bacteria
Antibacterial peptide給細菌
and in a test tube
而且在試管內
Then eventually, do you think it will still have a Resistant in the end?
那Eventually你覺得它會不會最後還是會有Resistant?
Yes, this is something I havent dared to talk about just now, and I havent talked about it yet
會,這就是我剛剛沒有一直不敢講,還沒有講的一個東西
Now based on the current literature report, it is reported that there is no antibacterial bacteria produced in nature
現在以目前的文獻報告,報導在自然界裡面沒有發現抗抗菌態的細菌產生
But we are in the laboratory, and some literatures have reported
但是我們在實驗室裡面,有些文獻已經報導了
Antimicrobial bacteria can be produced in the artificial mode in the laboratory
在實驗室用人工的模式是可以產生抗抗菌態的細菌
I just had a picture to tell you
我剛剛有一張圖有告訴大家說
In the antibacterial state, it will actually enter the bacteria, from DNA to RNA, to the process of protein
抗菌態它其實也會進到細菌裡面,一直DNA到RNA,到蛋白質的過程
that also produces what's called an antimicrobial state of bacteria
那個也就會產生所謂的抗抗菌態的細菌
But in our lab I once had a research creature that was also interesting
但是在我們實驗室我曾經有一個研究生物也很有趣
I asked him to help me deal with the bacteria with EPI
我就叫他幫我用EPI去處理細菌
At the beginning, did we pull the MIC from 1/10 or 1/4?
我們剛開始是拉從10分之1倍還是4分之1倍的MIC下去處理
Keep dealing with us until the end seems to be able to reach 10 times the MIC
一直處理我們到最後好像可以到10倍的MIC
But bacteria can still freeze eggs
但是細菌都還可以冷卵
But I didn't continue to do the experiment later, because originally this experiment should be doing the so-called molecular biology tool called Potonomic,
但是後面我沒有繼續做實驗下去,因為本來這個實驗做下去是應該在做所謂的分子生物的工具叫Potonomic,
It is to let the so-called two-dimensional capacitance sudden change interview to see what protein has changed,
就是讓所謂的二維電容突改面訊就下去看到有什麼蛋白質產生變化了,
But because of the relationship between ability and financial resources at that time, we did not continue to do it.
但因為那時候能力財力的關係,所以我們沒有繼續做下去,
Lets still quote what I just said at the beginning, we want to be like Switzerland, our laboratory is orderly like Switzerland,
我們就還是引述我剛開頭講的話,我們要像瑞士一樣,我們實驗室有秩序像一個瑞士一樣,
We want to be small and beautiful, so I focus on doing other things and keep asking,
我們要小而美,所以我就專注去做其他的一直追下去問,
Should it still be the skin, that is, the skin or the intestinal tract is the main source?
是不是應該還是皮,就是皮膚或是腸道是主要的來源嗎?
No, the anti-smoke carbon actually comes from other sources. For example, there is an anti-smoke carbon called Hip-Cidine.
不是,抗菸碳其實他來源,譬如說有一個抗菸碳叫Hip-Cidine,
H-E-P-C-I-D-I-N, which is produced by the liver,
H-E-P-C-I-D-I-N,它是從肝臟產生出來的,
It just came out of human urine when it was discovered
它剛才發現的時候是從人類的尿液裡面出來的
Payback here is posted on JB7
這邊Payback發表在JB7上面
It is from human urine to perform the so-called HPLC
就是從人類的尿液裡面它去打所謂的HPLC
Then found a Farcman inside
然後發現有一個Farcman裡面
It found that there is a so-called antibacterial effect
它發現這裡面有所謂的抗菌的一個效果
So it still thinks to go back and trace this gene
所以它還覺得說回去追溯說這個基因
Where does its product come from?
它的產物是從哪一個源頭是從哪邊出來的
Our more interesting question is to say
我們比較有趣的問題就是說
all the fish in every organ
所有的魚在每一個器官裡面
In fact, we do RNA analysis
其實我們做RNA的分析
We can know that there will be so-called EPI in almost every place
我們可以知道幾乎每一個地方都會有所謂的EPI的產生
But on the epidermis, it produces more RNA
但是它表皮上面它產生的比較多在RNA上面
right
對
professor again
教授再請教你一下
The professor advocated to eat more of this oxygen fish
教授這麼提倡說多吃這個氧質魚
Because it contains antibacterial properties, right?
因為它含有抗菌態對不對
In this way, if we often eat this oxygen fish contains antibacterial
這樣子我們如果常常吃這個氧質魚含有抗菌態
Does that reduce our overall inflammation?
那是不是可以降低我們整體的發炎的狀況
Eating more fish will make the body less prone to inflammation
多吃魚會身體就比較不容易發炎
Is it this way
是不是這樣
Thanks
謝謝
I dare not talk about this issue again
這個問題我不敢再這邊講
But I think eating more fish is good
但是我覺得多吃魚有好處
Because there are DH and NTM on the fish
因為魚上面還有DH跟NTM
Then it seems that the fish is also better than the four-horned animal. Will I be killed?
然後好像魚也比四隻角的動物我會不會被打死了
Fish is also a better source of meat than four-horned animals.
魚比四隻角的動物那個蓄產業的那個肉質的來源也還更好
It's also better quality
它的品質也更好
I think it should be like this
我覺得應該是這樣子
Eating more fish, I think, should have some effect on immune inflammation
多吃魚我覺得應該有對免疫發炎應該有一些功力
Because we usually eat cod liver oil?
因為我們平常都會吃魚肝油嘛
Cod liver oil has been verified to have some DHEPA
魚肝油已經驗證有一些DHEPA
Our laboratory has conducted experiments on EPA and DHEPA in inhibiting immune inflammation
我們試驗室有做EPA跟DHEPA在抑制免疫發炎的實驗
Well, we have recently verified that it really suppresses immune inflammation.
那我們最近有驗證它真的有抑制免疫發炎的反應的實驗
ok four people please
好,四人請
Hello, teacher
老師你好
What I want to ask is the ecological center
我想要問就是那個生態中間
Have you thought about modifying several amino acid regions to change its function like this?
你要想過就是可能Modify幾個安基酸區讓它的功能改變這樣子嗎
Recently, edited by Paver in the so-called Science Report
最近有編Paver在所謂的科學報導
On a magazine called Scientist Report
叫做Scientist Report的雜誌上面
Someone used two Modify and two amino acids
有人利用兩個Modify兩個安基酸
It can be successfully expressed in the protein expression system
就可以很成功的在蛋白質表達系統裡面表現
we are doing this too
我們也在做這件事情
But for now, I still want to go back to what you said just now that we want to do
但是目前我還是要回到剛剛您講的我們有想要做
But we're still waiting for the mayor's financial and human input.
但是我們還是在等市長的財力跟人力的投入
Let me add so as not to mislead everyone that you can be sterilized just to eat fish
我補充一下免得誤導大家說為了吃魚就可以讓你殺菌
When you have liver disease, it's not just eating fish that can cure liver disease
當你肝臟的時候不是靠吃魚就可以治療肝臟的疾病
Then the food goes down and is digested by the food
那吃的東西下去經過食物消化
Basically this has been broken down
基本上這個都已經被分解了
The case of becoming a single low and single short paragraph counts
變成單低單小段的案例算
He may no longer have the ability to fight bacteria
他可能已經沒有抗菌的能力了
Please don't mislead everyone
這個要大家不要誤導
just mentioned
就是剛剛有提到說
Some antimicrobial products are commercially available
市面上可以買到一些抗菌生產
That thing depends on how you use it
那個東西看你怎麼用
if you just eat it
你只要拿來吃的話
I believe it's probably 99.99% broken down
我相信可能99.99%都被分解掉
probably useless
可能都沒有用
So don't take it easy on the Internet
所以不要輕心網路上說
Which antibacterial product to buy can treat what
哪一個抗菌生產買來可以治療什麼
And you eat and fight
而且你用吃的跟用打的
completely different from a certain effect
跟某個效果完全不同
And the bacteria it kills may be completely different infections
而且殺的菌可能完全不同的感染
So don't buy it for yourself
所以不要自己隨便買來亂用
right
對
Recently, there seems to be a so-called marine ecology on the Internet
最近好像網路上有所謂的海洋生態
A lot of people
很多人
I saw on the Internet that there is a so-called marine ecology for sale
我在網路上看到有所謂的海洋生態在賣
eat and fight
吃跟打跟
Actually it's a different story
其實這是不同的故事
What I said today is that I hope everyone eats fish
我今天所謂希望大家吃魚
Eating fish and killing bacteria like you are two different things
吃魚跟你那麼殺菌這是兩碼的事
Yes, Mr. Liao thinks
對 廖老師想
But I encourage everyone to eat fish because I hope to be able to
但是我鼓勵大家吃魚是希望能夠
Everyone attaches great importance to the industry of water beach farming
大家重視水灘養殖的產業
I hope everyone eats more fish
也就是希望大家多吃魚
So I add carbon dioxide to beef
所以我對牛肉是增加二氧化碳的
So eating more fish won't cause this kind of problem
所以多吃魚不會有這種問題
My purpose is to hope that everyone can eat more fish
我的目的是希望大家能夠多吃魚
Pay more attention to the aquaculture industry
多重視水產養殖的產業
Best Seas
Best Seas
please teach me
請教一下
Chen Jiaojiao
陳教徒
Do you think the three are easier to obtain
你覺得三種比較容易取得
Or is it better to say that these three effects are better?
還是說這三種的效果比較好
good question
這問題問得很好
In fact, because when I went to Linhai Research Station,
其實因為我當初去林海研究站的時候
I still have to tell my history
我還是回到必須講一下我歷史
When going to Linhai Research Station
去林海研究站的時候
At first we just hoped
當初我們就是希望
Make a little contribution to Taiwan's aquaculture industry
對台灣的水產養殖產業有一點貢獻
The aquaculture industry was
當初水產養殖產業
On the turtle fish is the albino coccus infection
在烏龜魚上面就是煉球菌的感染
The grouper is infected with viruses and bacteria
石斑魚上面就是病毒跟細菌菌感染
So I started with these two types of fish as animals for my experiments
所以我先找這兩種魚做我的實驗的動物
Do you know what I mean
你知道我的意思嗎
right
對
Do you have any other questions
還有什麼問題嗎
Since grouper
既然石斑魚
These fish have their own antimicrobial ecology
這些魚本身就有抗菌生態
But these bacteria can still infect these animals
可是這些細菌還是會感染這些動物
So it must be said that only ecologists kill a certain bacterium
所以勢必是說只有生態者是殺某個細菌
But other bacteria still won't kill
可是其他細菌還是不會殺
So this fish can also be infected by bacteria
所以這個魚同樣會被細菌感染
right
對不對
Teacher Liao asked a question
廖老師問到問題
It is similar to antibiotics that have the so-called broad-spectrum effect and load-carrying effect
就是類似抗生素有所謂的廣效性跟載效性
The antibacterial ecology is the same, there is a so-called broad-spectrum antibacterial ecology
抗菌生態也一樣的有所謂的廣效性的抗菌生態
Antibacterial Ecology with Loading Effect
跟載效性的抗菌生態
I just gave that example
我剛才舉那個例子
That is to say, a HIP-STIDM was found on humans
就是說人類上面發現一個HIP-STIDM
HEP-CIDM
HEP-CIDM
We also found this antibacterial ecology on turtle fish
在烏龜魚上面我們也有發現這種抗菌生態
It is the so-called load-carrying antimicrobial ecology
它就是所謂的載效性的抗菌生態
For example, it may only kill certain types of bacteria
譬如說它可能只有殺某幾種細菌
API can actually kill many, many bacteria
API其實它可以殺很多很多的細菌
it's like in our movie
它類似在我們的電影裡面
It is a broad-spectrum bacterium
它是一個廣效性的細菌
Broad-spectrum antimicrobial ecology
殺廣效性的抗菌生態
Not for this fish will it be
並不是給這個魚上面會不會
It may take further research to find out.
這可能還要再做研究才知道
May I ask that Kang Juntai how to lock the pathogen
請問一下就是那個康俊台要怎麼鎖定病原體
what he wants
就是他要怎麼
Just said a certain concentration
就是剛剛說一定濃度
In fact, Shanghai will destroy normal cells
其實上海會破壞正常細胞
at lower concentrations
在比較低濃度的濃度下
Just like normal cells and pathogenic cells
就一樣有正常細胞跟病原體的細胞
How does Kang Juntai lock the cells of pathogens?
那康俊台要怎麼鎖定病原體的細胞
then go from his pattern
然後去從他的模式
you asked another very interesting question
你問到另外一個很有趣的問題
This is what we have said
這也是我們有講
Because hand in hand to many molecular mechanisms
因為牽手到很多的分子機制
simply means to say
簡單的意思就是講
Kang Juntai has the so-called water-clearing and water-carrying properties
康俊台有所謂的清水性跟輸水性
On normal cells and on bacteria
在正常細胞上面跟細菌上面
The composition of his cell membrane or cell arm is the same as that of normal cells
他的細胞膜或細胞臂上的組成跟正常細胞
normal cells are different
正常細胞是不一樣的
So Kangkang will suffer from this
所以康康他會受過這種
This leading force to
這種前引的力量到
so-called bacterial
所謂的細菌的
It's the reason why the positive and negative are finer
就是正負向細的原因
he will be drawn to it
他會吸引到那上面去
will not be compared with normal cells at low concentrations
不會跟正常細胞在低濃度
done at very low concentrations
很低的濃度之下做
interaction like this
interaction這樣子
right
對
what's the problem
什麼問題嗎
students high school students have
學生高中生有沒有
Yes or no
是不是
Excuse me
那個請問
can i ask the professor a question
可以問教授一個問題嗎
That's Kang Juntae
就是那個康俊泰
mainly in the cell volume
主要是在細胞容體內
still in cell pool
還是在細胞池內
that's what i saw
就是我看過
Someone on the internet wrote that
那個網路上有人寫說
He is the cell
他是把細胞
After bacteria eat
細菌吃進去之後
Then use the container to enter the food bubble
再用容體進入那個食泡
break down the bacteria
把細菌分解掉
You said that Kang Juntai eats bacteria
你說康俊泰把細菌吃
no is
沒有 就是
that's the time
就是那次去
Test cells
驗細胞
dead cells
去世細胞
after eating the bacteria
把細菌吃掉之後
it forms a food bubble
它會形成一個食泡
Then dissolve and go in
然後溶體再進去
Is the antibacterial Taiwan really in the solution?
那抗菌臺灣真的是在溶體裡面的嗎
no antibacterial Taiwan in solution
沒有 抗菌臺灣在溶體
I am in antibacterial Taiwan it will not go to dissolve
我在抗菌臺灣它不會去溶體
Because there are too many enzymes in the solution
因為溶體裡面有太多酵素
it will take it away
它會把它帶去掉
will break it down
會把它分解掉
So why did we just talk about antibacterial tables
所以為什麼我們剛剛有談到抗菌臺
Will you be afraid of the role of eggs from plums?
會不會怕蛋來自梅的作用
because you have a good idea
因為你這個想法很好
I
我
you ask him this question
你問他這個問題
I ask to do
我問做
I have another question for you
我對你另外一個問題
In the process of cancer drug development
在癌症藥物開發的過程裡面
do you know
你知道嗎
There will be liposomes
會有用微脂體
buy so-called chemically synthesized drugs
包買所謂的化學合成的藥物
like cranberries
像小紅莓
Then the cranberries are brought into the cells
然後小紅莓帶到細胞裡面去的
When cancer cells go inside
癌症細胞裡面去的時候
It marks the time when the drug is brought into the cancer cell
它標榜藥物帶到癌症細胞裡面去的時候
Why is this chemically synthesized drug
為什麼這個化學合成的藥物
it can kill that cancer cell
它可以殺那個癌細胞
because it is in the so-called Libosome
因為它在所謂的Libosome
That's when liposomes are brought in
就是微脂體帶進去的時候
Usually go to the Lysofone you just mentioned
通常會到你剛剛講的Lysofone裡面去
close up
攏微填面去
In the agricultural media, it is a chemically synthesized drug, so it will not be hydrolyzed by these
到農媒體裡面它是化學合成的藥物,所以它不會被這些水解掉
At the beginning, our laboratory also wanted to wrap it in the liposome, hold it in the hand, and send it to the cell.
我們實驗室當初也想要包在微脂體裡面,拉著手裡面,送到細胞裡面去
Then through the same picture is to kill the cells, but it is so dead, this experiment has not been done
然後透過一樣的圖就是殺害細胞,但是好死不死,這實驗沒有做
After discussing with the teachers of the Chemistry Institute, it was just when Mr. Li Xianqiong was discussing
我們經過跟化學所的老師討論,就是剛剛李賢瓊老師討論的時候
He told me that this will definitely be borrowed by the agricultural media and agricultural disintegration, so this way is not feasible
他就跟我講這一定會被農媒體,農解體代借掉,所以這條路是不可行的
Exactly like this, so we didn't do cell experiments
一模這樣子,所以我們就沒有去做細胞實驗
I speculate that the anti-disease is secreted outside the so-called cells, and kills the bacteria first
我推估抗病態是分泌在所謂的細胞的外面,先把細菌給殺掉
Then some giant cells will gobble it up, like this
然後一些巨式細胞才會去把它吞噬掉,這樣子
It should not be in the agricultural media
它應該不會在農媒體裡面
Excuse me, professor, I would like to ask a question
不好意思 教授我想請問一個問題
It was the time when the Anti-Tai Army committed suicide and killed the Aijin continuation package
就是這個抗太軍他殺這個愛晉續包的時候
He does not need to adjust a specific concentration to produce a specific cell
他不是要調特定的濃度才能對某特定的細胞產生
just be able to kill him
就是能夠殺掉他這樣
So the question I want to ask is
那我想請問的問題是說
Can he kill this?
這個殺掉這個他能不會
Will he be able to hit the ground running or will he stay there
他是能夠一往打擊還是他會留下有
Other Aijin Sequel Packs
其他的愛晉續包
Then consider the study of love stem cells
那這樣考慮到愛幹細胞的學作
Is it very likely that he will relapse
他復發的可能性大不大
You asked a good question too
你這問題也問得很好
Now that you are admitted to the graduate school, can you come to my laboratory?
你現在考上研究所可不可以來我這邊實驗室
do an experiment
做一下實驗
Pull the graduate first
先拉一下研究生一下
really good question for you
對你這問題問得真的很好
meeting
會
He can't kill all the love cells
他沒有辦法全部都殺掉所有的愛細胞
so we just saw
所以我們剛剛你們看到
This is what I told my lab colleagues
這是我跟實驗室的同事講
This is what our first generation thought
這是我們第一代的想法
In fact, the first generation of this process
第一代其實這種過程
everyone is very
大家都很
Everyone can general laboratory
大家都能夠一般的實驗室
We now have ideas for second-generation drug development
我們現在有第二代藥物開發的想法
However, since it has not been made
但是,因為還沒有做出來
So it's not convenient for me to talk to you here
所以我不方便在這邊跟你講
You can wait a minute and I will tell you later
你等一下可以到後面我跟你講
Because many people will know
因為這樣講很多人就會知道
then we are a small laboratory
那我們是小實驗室
you just saw there were only a few cats
你剛看到只有幾隻貓
my thoughts i think there are a lot of fresh ideas
我的想法我覺得有很多新鮮的想法
It's not really suitable for you to listen to it under the hall broadcast
其實不適合在大廳廣播之下講給你聽
except i made it
除了我成功了
I'll tell you when I succeed
等我成功我再跟你們講
We want to develop second generation drugs
我們希望開發第二代藥物
It can be similar to the current targeted drug
就是能夠類似現在的標靶藥物一樣
it only targets cancer cells
它只針對癌細胞
to the cancer cell
到癌細胞那邊
Antibacterial tires will kill that special cancer cell
抗菌胎就會去殺那個特殊性的癌細胞
including cancer cells as well as bacteria
包括癌細胞跟細菌一樣
That is to say, from the broad-spectrum antibacterial
也就是說從廣效性的抗菌胎
Make it antibacterial only against certain bacteria
讓它變成只針對某種細菌的抗菌的
Antibacterial tires against certain bacteria
抗某種細菌的抗菌胎
Biotechnology should be able to do it now
現在生物科技應該可以做得到
but we're going to try
但是我們要試試看
None of us should have done this
我們這些應該都還沒有人做
we have seen cooperation
我們有看過配合
wait we have that idea
等會我們有那個想法
So when I'm done
所以等我做完以後
if successful
如果成功了
I will listen
我會聽講
I'll wait and hear what we think
我等一下可以聽講我們的想法
but you don't
但是你不要這樣
He'll be like an antibody, a mutation that's never passed on
他會像抗體一樣會一直不傳的突變
mutation mutation
突變突變
disease resistance
抗病
he will
他會對
he will be like
他會像
Won't
不會
He's basically an elite constant
他基本上他是精英常物
he won't mutate
他不會突變
you say something like
你說類似
similar bacterial mutation
類似細菌突變
right
對不對
He doesn't look like a bacterial mutation
他不會類似細菌突變這樣子
The question is like an antibody
問的是像抗體一樣的
Is it an antibody
是不是抗體
Object antibody
對像抗體
Antibody V region
抗體的V region
V region
V region
Does the row produce antibodies?
排會不會產生抗體
no
不是
Will there be a change
會不會產生變化
But
可是
The anti-disease he does not use antibodies
那個抗病他他不是利用抗體的
idea to sterilize
觀念去殺菌
He went directly to sterilize by himself
他是自己直接上去殺菌
He said it will keep changing
他說會不會一直變化
Won't
不會
Antibodies won't
抗體不會啊
Because he's an ATGOTTG he's a certain gene product
因為他是一個ATGOTTG 他是一定的基因產物
Do bacteria have a gene?
細菌會不會有一個基因?
bacteria
細菌
Bacteria will target this type of antibacterial state to
細菌它會針對這種類型的抗菌態來
Yes, so this time I just repeated the report to you
對 所以這次我剛剛有重複跟大家報告
Now in the state of artificial synthetic mode in the laboratory
現在在實驗室的人工的合成模式的狀態之下
We are bacteria that can find antimicrobial states
我們是可以找到抗抗菌態的細菌
However, there has not been any report in the natural environment
但是在自然環境裡面還沒有任何一篇報告
tell us that there are bacteria that are resistant to certain antibacterial states
告訴我們說有抗某種抗菌態的細菌產生
I just think it's in the process of evolution
我才想就是在演化過程中
Maybe there is a change in the antibacterial status
也許抗菌態有變化不一定
isn't it? in the process of evolution
是不是?在演化的過程中
Yes, you want to talk about how the antibacterial state evolves
對 你是想要講抗菌態怎麼演化
To the question of the evolution of the antimicrobial state
對 抗菌態演化這個問題
I can't answer you
我也沒有辦法回答你
Although I have always wanted to find us Lin Yaying
雖然我一直很想要找我們林涯瑩
Just when another teacher called Mr. Taitian
就在另外一個老師叫泰田老師
He seems to be doing evolution
他好像是在做演化
Then I want to ask him how to evolve to do experiments
然後想要問他演化怎麼來做實驗
But I still have to go back
但是我還是要回到剛剛
Because every day in the laboratory we are still a small satellite TV small scale
因為每一天實驗室我們還是小衛視小規模
We can only do research on certain research topics
我們只能針對某一些研究課題下去做研究
yes too many questions
對 有太多問題了
What everyone was concerned about just now is that
剛才大家在關心的就是說
Will this antibacterial tire be treated for a long time?
這個抗菌胎它會不會因為處理很久
Those pathogenic bacteria were originally effective
那些病研菌本來是有效的
Being resistant to drugs is like resisting a dead pig
被人抗藥性像是抗死豬一樣
I personally think this means
那這個我個人覺得就是說
The main antibacterial tires have a large drug resistance
主要的抗菌胎的作藥抗藥體大
It has a stop model and a copped model
它有stop的model還有coppedmodel
That is, it will impress the membrane
也就是會把membrane打動
This is mainly if the drug resistance does not
這是主要如果這種不會產生抗藥性
But antibacterial tires are still consistent
但是抗菌胎還有一致
DNA replication or RNA routing
DNA的複製或是RNA的轉路
or as a transfer of blank paper
或是當白紙的轉移
This is very similar to the mechanism of action of most current antibiotics.
那這個就很像目前大部分抗生素的作用機制
If its mechanism of action is mainly limited to that part
如果它的作用機制主要以那個部分為止的話
Antimicrobial resistance may develop
可能抗菌胎的抗藥性可能會產生
So it's two big
所以它是兩個大力
Most of them are to destroy the membrane, in simple terms, to impress
大部分都是把membrane破壞,簡單來講就打動
So cell disease bacteria, the cells inside the cells will be lost
所以細胞病人菌,細胞裡面的細胞都會流失
So the bacteria will be the first to meet, they won't be able to survive
所以細菌第一個會,就不能夠存活
Second, the membrane is moved too much, it robsick
第二個,membrane被打動太多,它就robsick掉
So in EM, you can see that many cells have been ground by cells and are not brittle
所以在EM裡面,就可以看到很多細胞被細胞磨了不脆片
The cell chips come out, so these are two types
細胞脆片就散出來,所以這是兩大類
It all depends on you, Kang Xintai, which one is the main mechanism of action?
完全看你這康信泰的,作用機制是以哪一個為主
mostly impressed
大部分是打動的
so this answers your question
所以這個可以回答您的問題
Well, the two times are about the same
好,這兩次時間差不多了
So now before it's over I'll announce that it's the next time
所以現在在結束前我預告就是下一次的
grateful
感謝
Director of Guoxing Lin Zuoyuan
國興林祚原間所長
The award is the memory of Japan in Taiwanese folk beliefs
出獎是台灣民間信仰中的日本記憶
I hope everyone will join in the night
希望大家永夜參加
sure there will be more than enough in this dinner
確定這個晚餐中的會有餘
then we introduce again
那我們再次介紹
Thank you again Dr. Chen for your wonderful association
再次謝謝陳博士的精采聯想